What's up, people?
It's time for Isaac.
The addiction continues.
I'm trying to contain my excitement.
Just a bit.
I'm too vulnerable when I let my excitement overflow.
Does Oliver do it?
Yep.
It's time for Isaac.
And guys, I'm too excited.
I'm going in.
It's time.
Look at that, the end.
Well, we are not going to believe that.
Because this ain't the end.
Hold on, was there anything I needed to check here?
Play Lazarus to unlock new character.
Always head in the clouds.
Right, that was a clue, I think, for something.
Bring him the photo.
That one, I'm still not quite sure about.
Go to angel-looking church area.
That one, you know what?
I feel like that one is not relevant anymore.
Or maybe it is.
I'm going to leave it.
Observations.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's fine.
All that is pretty cool.
Actually, I'm going to move this up a little bit.
I'm actually going to move everything up a little bit.
Make it nice and needy.
Or tidy.
Tidy.
Tight, tight, tight.
All right, let's go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Maybe we start with a challenge.
Oh, look at this.
We got to do four of them.
We do it in order.
Darkness falls.
What's that about?
I wish I could randomize the channel.
The, what do you call it?
The challenge.
Okay, so I need to remember how to do this.
Let's see, what is that item I have?
Razor blade.
Damages I6 to grant a damage up for the current room.
Unlimited use, but damages every time.
Damages red hearts before other heart types.
You know, that is kind of fitting for... Are we the whore?
I think we're the whore.
Dark matter?
Chance to, for tears to apply fear effect?
Chance increases with luck.
Okay.
Pentagram increases devil angel room chance, except it doesn't.
It's at zero.
What do you mean?
Sacrificial dagger.
Orbital knife familiar that deals heavy contact damage and blocks enemy shots.
Okay.
And I can't see my HP.
Ooh, that is a little scary.
We have almost five damage.
Dude, this is going to be easy.
Am I crazy?
What's the catch here?
What's the catch?
Let's see what's going on.
There's probably something that's going to happen that's going to happen in my mind.
Wait, what?
Oh, there's a rock.
I just got saved by that knife.
Yeah, that's not a very good orbital there.
It's very close.
It needs to be further away.
Dude, the fear effect is nuts.
So I don't know how many hearts I have.
I don't know if I should self harm right now with the razor blade.
It could be risky.
Let's try it.
I'm going to fucking try it.
Oh, we immediately turn into a demon.
Okay, so hold on.
That means we started with two hearts.
Damages red hearts.
How much does it damage though?
Is it a full heart or half a heart?
That's got to be a full heart because I haven't taken damage.
Shit.
I may be in danger.
I'm going to go back.
Not yet.
I'm not ready.
Okay, this way.
I don't want to accidentally hit space bar now.
Imagine.
Ooh, this could be.
Okay.
Friends till the end.
Good.
I'm so scared.
Let's see here.
I guess I want to buy this.
Oh, I don't have enough money.
Shit, a blue heart right now would go hard.
Voodoo head.
Nah, not really feeling that.
If I buy this, I'm going to revert my demoness, right?
So I'm not going to do that.
I can't believe we can't find another coin.
Actually, I shouldn't have done self-harm.
I should have walked in here.
Dude, at least get like an upside with the self-harm.
I just now realized.
That was dumb.
Oh well.
Okay, let's see.
No, not this guy.
I'm going to die.
Maybe.
Oh God.
I don't trust like that.
This guy's going to, you know, get off his horse at some point.
Yeah.
What's happening now?
I don't know what's happening.
Yeah, we did it.
Give me that.
Ball of bandages.
Level up each time.
I just collect it.
Yeah, that's fine.
That's fine.
We still have four coins.
We have one bomb.
That's fine.
Wait, we briefly turned non-demon when we jumped down.
Did you see that?
Are we going to turn back to a demon now?
We are.
100% demon mode.
So it is always for sure.
Let's see what it says here.
What did I write?
Floor 215, 100% demon mode.
Okay.
We're on floor two now.
I'm going to try and keep track of that.
For real though, this time.
Oh, let's not go in there.
I can see my hearts now.
Beautiful.
I don't have any curses.
Oh shit.
Oh, that was close.
This guy
just hit me.
Pills are exciting.
He walked into fire.
I will eat it.
Oh, okay.
Got it.
This may be a mistake.
Yeah.
Oh, slalom, baby.
Or drift, whatever, Tokyo, you know?
Mega Man stuff.
I don't actually know the reference.
I'm a fake referenceer.
I make it up.
Okay.
There's someone else.
There you are.
Okay, not too bad.
I want more pills.
This is the reason I'm whoring, you know, to get pills.
Any tinted rocks?
No.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
It's chill.
Also, call me crazy, but have we not seen a treasure room yet?
Blow this up.
Yeah, that's massive.
I'm going to go back.
I need to confirm whether or not there's any treasure rooms here.
There may not be.
Maybe in this challenge there is none, you know?
It's a possibility.
I cannot destroy this fire, can I?
Oh yeah, I can, okay.
404!
Wait, what?
Hold on.
Mimics the effect of a random trinket-y troll?
Oh, that's an item?
Oh, that's weird.
Hold on.
Huh.
Okay.
How come I could read what that was?
Because I've never had it before.
Shouldn't that have been...
Oh no, I picked up a heart accidentally.
It spawned out of the frickin' poop.
No!
I can do self-harm though?
Well, that's gonna remove an entire heart.
So maybe I pick up another half-heart.
Actually, yeah, let's do that.
We're totally chilling.
I grabbed this.
Look at that!
That's how you do it.
Smart or what?
If I was on one of those, you know, hot or not sites, but it's smart or not, people would swipe right on that.
100%.
I'm just saying now.
Sir, come here.
Nice.
Come on, man!
I'm doing all my work!
That's fine.
Not a big deal.
Also, I have bad news.
I don't think we're gonna have an opportunity to get a treasure room here.
Maybe even a shop.
How do I think about it?
Yeah, I definitely have a lot less damage now, but it's still good.
I mean, my damage is respectable.
Oh, shop!
Fuck yeah!
I don't have enough though.
Also, I'm not sure I wanna remove my razor.
Wait,
should I?
You know what I can do?
I can go step.
I can... oh, but wait, that's gonna consume blue, isn't it?
Shit, I can't do that.
We can't do that.
I'm gonna save my money.
Yeah, it pains me a little bit, but you know, it's alright.
Let's go!
Nine damage I have now.
I don't know why I said that in a Yoda voice or style, but I did.
Don't be afraid of me, come here!
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I'm gonna murder you!
Ooh, I have good damage.
Damage is good.
Yeah, come on then.
No biggie.
Magic eight ball increases chance of planetariums.
Yeah, I've heard that before.
I don't believe that for a second.
The Emperor teleports to the boss room.
You know what?
I'm gonna pick up this heart.
We're gonna go in here.
We're gonna...
Oh shit, hold on, hold on.
Scary.
I can't think.
We gotta destroy these first.
This is a way to permanently have the effect active.
What do I want though?
Probably this one.
Apply sphere to enemies.
Oh, we're gonna be the ultimate fear factor then.
You know what I mean?
More tears?
Shot speed?
That's just gonna, you know, multiply our already very high damage.
I like it.
And we're gonna forever stay on this form now.
This was a great choice.
Now we gotta not take damage and grab black hearts and blue hearts.
And we're chilling.
Also, hold on.
There's a fly inside of my ear.
One second.
Alright, there we go.
Let's go up here.
I'm not afraid.
Demon's tail?
Sure.
I am a demon already.
I embrace the demon.
What happened?
Oh, I didn't want to pick that up.
That was a mistake.
Uh-oh.
I think we're okay.
Stop picking that up.
Dude, I can barely see the air on the floor because it's so, you know, it's camouflaged.
It's blended in real well.
Dude, my aim is absolutely atrocious today.
Where are you going?
Oh, my range is not good enough.
And that should do it.
Bomb for me.
Oh, fuck.
Actually, let's kill these guys first.
Yeah, beautiful.
Very safe.
Okay.
Going this way now.
I am not gonna use a bomb here.
Not yet, at least.
Let's get it jumping.
Okay, we got an extra bomb.
Maybe I will go back then.
Can I destroy two flies with one smash?
Here.
If I... nah, probably not.
Let's take that one.
I should have done it near the wall in case of a secret.
Immediate regrets.
Oh, we got another bomb.
So let's do it here now.
Ah!
I clicked the wrong button!
Fuck!
Wait, what's the button for bomb?
Oh, right.
Dude, I don't know what the fuck is wrong with me.
Uh, spawn to block donation.
Yeah, that's too late for that.
Teleport to the bot?
No, I don't want to do that.
Mistakes were made.
And not that it matters too much right now.
It's fine.
Oh, yoy.
Come at me!
Okay, we're gonna kill them like this.
Yeah.
Smort.
Not bad.
Ooh!
A door open somewhere?
Love that.
Now to find it.
We may need to step for that, actually.
I think the next step to that is to step.
Steppity step.
Gimme.
Dude, lots of money I'm getting.
Why am I Yoda speaking today?
I don't know what's happening.
Come here!
Okay.
4.5 volt.
Dealing damage to enemies.
Gradually recharges active items.
Active items no longer gain charges.
Okay, what was that one?
What was the effects of most?
No, I don't like that.
I don't want to Ah well.
Wait, my bombs are now golden.
Hold on a minute.
What does that mean?
I just did something significant here.
So my key was golden because I picked up the golden key thingy.
And now I swapped it.
So I'm guessing I no longer have the key effect.
But I have a bomb effect now.
Maybe I can open doors with the bombs.
Temperance.
We don't know what that is.
I'm actually tempted to buy another bomb.
Man, this is a shit shop.
Maybe this means I have infinite bombs.
Hold on.
We're gonna blow you up.
It's a golden bomb.
Infinite bombs!
No way!
Okay, that's crazy.
We're gonna be blowing up everything.
All the secrets belong to me.
Short fuse.
Oh no, I don't want that.
Even though my bombs are good, they're not that good.
I'm too scared of damaging myself.
Moving on.
Wait, I bet it's here.
How good am I?
The problem now is though, we don't have enough keys.
We gotta remedy that somehow.
Dude, I'm rich AF.
A pencil.
Every 15 shots fire at burst.
Ooh, I like that one.
What does my current one do actually?
8% of drop hearts are replaced with keys.
All heart drops.
Oh, Demon's Tale is actually insane.
We need this.
We need the Demon's Tale.
Oh my god.
That's wild.
Yeah, become afraid of me.
No, no, no, no, no.
Don't like that.
I don't want to go in there.
Actually, I can take a look.
Would love to step, but again, wrong character, wrong time, wrong situation.
Ah, but I can get in here.
Wait, that's not a black heart.
I thought every heart was gonna be a black heart now.
I was lied to.
I like that.
Hmm, let's go here.
What the heck man?
Okay.
Dude, my fear effects are crazy.
They get afraid of me when they're close to me and when I hit them with my shots.
How good is that, huh?
I would say it's pretty damn good.
Oh, sets Isaac's health to one red heart.
Wait, I wonder if this is gonna spawn black hearts then.
Fuck.
If I didn't have any blue hearts right now, I would totally go step.
No, I wouldn't because I only have one heart that I can use.
So, never mind.
I feel like I should be destroying more mushrooms everywhere.
Have I seen any?
None in here.
Definitely want to destroy the mushrooms.
That's a big thing.
Oh yeah, this room.
I'm just gonna blow everything up.
I've never seen three secret rooms.
I wonder if it's possible.
Oh, I'll take that I guess.
Okay, take me!
Polyphallus!
No, polycephalus.
Polycephalus?
Not sure how to pronounce that.
Hey, I got infinite bombs for you.
That's for you.
Dude, bombs are kind of good.
Yeah, the bombs from the... what's that?
Perfection?
Taking damage destroys the trinket?
Brother.
That's crazy.
See, I would love to go in here, but I can't afford to.
But I will peek.
I technically could afford to.
Grant's flight?
Oh my god.
Dude, should we go fucking balls to the wall?
Ooh, I'm tempted.
I'm tempted.
Oh wait, this... no, I didn't even see the two blue hearts.
Hold on a minute.
I missed the two blue hearts.
I saw the red heart and I was like, let's fucking go.
It's not happening.
I'm not taking any of those.
Dude, Perfection A+, I'm an amazing student.
We can't take damage now.
This is so cool.
How come I can see the description of the item, though, when I haven't had it before?
Before I picked it up, isn't that weird?
Oh, we're in this place.
Blooded caves.
We're gonna take damage immediately, by the way.
This is just the law of the universe.
How am I gonna use my luck?
Dude, we should really pay attention now to what I'm getting lucky with.
So we can try and understand exactly what luck affects.
Because this is one of those cases where we can actually meaningfully check it statistically.
Assuming I don't get hit by some random bullshit, right?
Okay, average chest reward.
Noted.
Pretty good room items.
Maybe that's what it's affecting?
Also, I can definitely get in there.
Yeah, give me that.
Wait, how come my bombs are no longer golden?
Wait a minute.
Huh?
Was it only for one floor?
That's so sad.
No, I thought I was gonna find all the secrets in this run.
Whoa!
Okay, let's be careful there.
Good night.
Oi, yo, yo!
Okay, not bad, not bad.
I can't get to that, unfortunately.
Can I?
No, I can't walk on this.
We have a fight room.
Closed, maybe for the best.
Get scared.
Be scared of me, be scared of me.
I'm leaving.
Come here.
I'm also scared of them, actually.
This goes both ways right now.
Fear is so good.
Okay, no enemies or what?
I could blow my way across here.
Let me think about it.
Three bombs?
Yeah, okay, let's do it.
We gotta check the lock here.
Also, I think that had a different effect as well.
Oh yeah, taking damage is always the trinkets.
Yeah, perfection only lasts as long as you're perfect, right?
As soon as you take damage, you're not perfect anymore.
You know, I wonder if I only got the perfection because I reached that point in the run without taking any damage.
The only damage I took was with the razor, right?
Chewed pen.
10% chance to fire a slowing shot.
Increases with luck.
Yo!
Ah, but that's not gonna work with my... I can't... unless I have two trinkets later.
Huh.
Uh oh.
We're gonna have some bombs in here.
Yay!
Come on!
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So far, so good, I guess.
Oh, no thanks.
I will gladly skip that.
What do you want?
More bombs is good.
We love that.
I'm surprised I haven't taken damage yet.
I'm totally jinxing it now as well, just so you know.
So many hearts and I can't use them.
Feels bad, yo.
Nice.
I'm gonna... wait, can I move this?
No.
No, I don't have a key.
Oh my god, we gotta get into the shop, though.
With this amount of money in the bank.
What a sniper shot.
Insanity.
We got a key.
Huge.
Oh, we take that off.
Oh my god, what's that?
Blackheart immunity to floor curses?
Immunity to negative effects from certain items?
Wait!
Immunity to negative effect from perfection, maybe?
Okay, it still says taking damage destroys the trinket.
Maybe not, then.
Member card.
All shops contain a trap door, right?
Okay.
The special shop sells... Yeah, obviously we take that.
Let's go have a look at that.
Dude, this challenge is so much fun.
Laus.
A small chance of spawning a blue spider any time Isaac is in a room.
Nope.
Unknown room.
Ooh.
I'll be buying that.
I'm also gonna be buying this.
And I'm gonna also buy this.
It's Jira.
Ah, you know what?
I probably should have done this first.
Because this is the one that duplicates, right?
Fuck.
I could probably have duplicated the Blackheart.
Shit.
Oh well.
I will buy a key because I'm lacking.
Sounds good.
I think we go for the boss.
Wish me luck.
It's... Oh, it's the mega fatty.
Surely I'll take damage here.
He's gonna puke.
Yeah.
Okay, okay.
Careful.
He's gonna jump at some point as well, right?
No.
Unless I'm misinformed.
So far he is not jumping.
Oh, oh, oh, okay.
Nice.
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
A snack!
Ooh, wait, wait, wait.
Is this a good idea?
It is.
Because I can use the razor, baby.
Hahaha!
Not bad.
The razor is actually sick.
Um, no devil for me.
I'm just gonna go ahead and move on.
Yeah.
Let's go.
Not a bad first run to start off the day, huh?
I'm scared of the jump.
Perfection has been lost!
It was a good run, though.
It was a good run.
Um, go here.
Ooh, I don't want to waste my last key here.
I'm coming back later.
Although there was a key that could have grabbed there, I guess.
I do have the Jira.
I think I'm gonna save it until I find, like, a black heart or something.
Okay.
Oh, nah, mistakes were made.
Oh, thank you, birdie.
I appreciate it.
Golden poop.
I like...
I shall take it.
Oh, it wasn't a good one.
Unfortunately.
Oh, don't do this to me, man.
Uh, how am I gonna do this?
Oop.
Look, we even have the trap door in here!
It also works on these types of rooms where the guy is here.
That's kind of cool.
Hey, come here.
So much money.
All right.
Aw, sick.
Okay, so what do I want?
Sacrificial altar.
I can also reroll!
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on a minute now.
This is exciting.
Mom's box is more luck.
Sponsored trinkets.
It disables the effects.
What?
Oh, doubles the effects of trinkets.
Sacrificial altar is consumed to sacrifice up to two familiars chosen at random.
For each familiar sacrifice, one random devil room pedestal item is...
Whoa.
Wait, it's discounted and it's at 19.
That means this one was hella expensive.
Activating it also sacrifices each blue spider or flies spawning one coin each.
Ooh, I think I'm going to do it, dude.
Oh, I thought it would consume the knife as well.
Isn't that familiar, technically?
Oh, well, this is good, I guess.
Leviathan.
Take it.
Now, I think I'm going to reroll.
I could also come back later with some more money and think about it then.
Mom's box is too expensive.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Oh, wait, this dude in the bottom right is hanging out.
Kill him.
13 coins.
I could go for the boss.
Nah, not yet.
I want to find some more stuff first.
Oh, they're going to jump.
They're going to jump.
Come on, Kimi.
I need keys.
Any tinted rocks?
Doesn't look like it.
Oh, kill the TNT.
Wait, what happened?
Oh, there we go.
We got a key.
Oh, the Bible.
Telepathy for dummies.
Boaming tears in increased range.
Dude, I'm taking the Bible.
You can't stop me.
Yep, the Bible is mine.
Oh, wow.
Ooh, I'm in a spot here.
I'm okay, I'm okay.
That was a bit risky.
Wait, why am I...
Oh, wait a minute.
That's what's happening.
I forgot about the last effect about this one.
The fact that I can do this with the tears.
That's, yeah, right.
Let's see, I don't want to fly.
I do have a battery lying around as well, if I need to fly in multiple rooms.
A second door has opened.
Get him.
Another key is huge.
Actually, I guess it doesn't matter at this point, since we have the amazing key.
All right.
I don't want to fly here either.
I could start destroying some walls.
See if I can find a secret room.
It seems like a prime candidate.
All right, never mind.
What about here?
Okay, then.
Forget I asked.
The good news is, the Bible, that's pretty much a guaranteed kill on the mom.
Mom is out of here.
Let's not pick that up.
Very important.
No, thanks.
Time for the boss.
It's boss time.
Wait, should I pick something else up?
On the way, we can take a peek in here.
Hey, let's see if we find some money.
We do.
17 coins.
There was something else in the shop, right?
That I potentially wanted to buy.
Oh, this is free now.
Yeah!
Oh, nice.
Wait, I'm not going to pick this up yet, in case we get another blue heart.
Okay.
Okay, I'm going to take it then.
Shit.
Actually, let's see what we had here.
Oh, yeah, we can re-roll.
Let's do it.
I wonder if it's going to re-roll three items or only two.
Aha!
Oh, no, I barely don't have enough.
I would love the bar of soap, though.
Maybe we can get some money from the mushrooms.
Ooh.
Oh, okay.
Maybe I can get money by destroying this thing.
No, it re-rolled!
Fuck!
Okay, I need to note that down.
That's actually kind of important.
Observations.
Destroying re-roll machine.
Re-rolls items.
Good to know.
Dead Sea Scrolls?
I'm not really excited about that.
I'm excited about this, though.
It's Jera again.
So, if I do this, Jera.
That's free now.
Blood donation.
That's going to take a red heart.
So, yo, we can actually...
Oh, wait a minute now.
I have an idea.
We have red hearts lying around, don't we?
Well, not that many.
Some.
I'm going to heal up one red heart.
And then we're going to use the machine.
Gain a little bit more money.
Really squeezing every little advantage we can get here.
You may say this is overkill.
I say it's appropriate.
Still haven't found any secrets.
I have a feeling right here.
That's the last bomb!
Oh!
I shouldn't have done that.
Mistakes were made.
I should have used it on the machine.
Yeah!
Okay, two coins.
Better than nothing.
Oh, let's also grab the Jera.
Jera?
Jera, I think it was pronounced.
Jera.
The year of me dominating.
It was a beautiful year.
The fallen.
Let's try the Bible here!
I sentenced you to...
Okay.
Oh, didn't do anything, huh?
Oh, dude, I'm doing a lot of damage here.
Like, holy shit.
This is... this is real.
Oh, god.
Mistakes were made.
Taking too much damage.
Blood rights.
Take one heart of self-damage.
What is it?
What is with the self-damage in this run?
Uh, subsequent uses in the same room cost.
Half a heart consumes red hearts before...
You know what?
This is actually kind of good.
Uh, gain a tier 7 deal 40 damage.
It's just for the room.
Okay.
I'm going to keep my Bible.
I didn't mean to take that!
Guess we're going back to the blood machine.
Tell me it's still there.
I didn't blow it up, right?
No, because I didn't...
Thank god I used my bomb then.
Actually, this was optimized.
Now we get an extra coin.
This was all planned.
Insane gameplay.
Okay.
Let's go.
So this...
Oh, wait.
So this is actually going to be Mom now.
Yeah.
Let's make sure we have enough charges on the Bible to use it when it's time for Mom.
You're feared, huh?
Bob's rotten head.
Uh, yeah, why not?
Oh, it's an active.
Never mind.
Then I'm not interested.
No interest though.
I shall take that.
No!
I'm actually not sure I like this Eye of the Occult thing.
Fuck!
Yeah, that was tough.
That was a hard one.
At least we can gamble our sins away.
Nice.
All right, dude.
Give me some good stuff here.
I believe in you.
Oh, good start.
Dude.
I should have done it!
I will not forget it for next time.
God damn it.
I could have had so many black hearts.
Well, one more.
But you know, it's still a lot.
Hey, my bird is kind of saving me here.
Thanks.
I love this bird so much.
A real pal.
Oh, uh, no thanks.
Keep that to yourself.
Actually, no, no, no.
Yo.
We do want it.
We want it a lot.
The gambling session has been extended.
You love to see it.
A fresh deposit in the account.
Come on.
Oh, you know what?
Dude, I just had an idea.
You see these hearts right now?
I'm gonna leave them until I spawn a lot.
And then we're gonna Jira.
Dude.
Why didn't I think of this immediately?
This is genius.
Holy shit.
Oh, come on.
Give me some black hearts or some blue hearts or something.
Actually, any heart will do.
Even the red hearts make me happy right now.
Come on.
40% demon chance, by the way.
Okay, we're gonna leave those as well, because I think this counts with Jira.
Oh my god.
Would love to get a bomb as well, if you don't mind.
Sir, uh, man.
Madam.
12 coins left.
Maybe I should save some for a potential shop.
Obviously, I'm not gonna do that.
Come on, baby.
Okay, that's cool.
Man, if only step rooms took red hearts first, huh?
I would totally be stepping right now.
Ooh, I would be stepping so hard.
More keys.
Wait, does it also...
Wait, I wonder if Jira also duplicates...
Uh, money.
Bombs, okay.
Okay, one more coin after this.
And then it's time to go nuts.
You ready?
Last coin.
Very nice.
Okay, I'm actually gonna click on this first.
Don't pick it up.
Here we go.
I love it!
Jira, you're my best friend.
That is so freaking cool.
We keep donating, baby!
Infinite gambling!
It's insane.
Uh, more.
We're never gonna stop gambling.
Wait, what happens if I touch it again, though?
And I don't have any red hearts.
Wait, did that take a blue heart?
I'm not sure.
Oh, okay, it is.
It is taking...
I didn't mean to do it again!
I was an autopilot, I swear to god, dude.
What the fuck am I doing?
That was a mistake.
We fucked up there.
That's okay, it happens.
When you win as much as I do right now, you gotta have some downs to have the ups, you know?
I can't believe I did that, though.
That was absolutely devastating.
But look at my money go up.
Stonks go up!
Nice.
More.
Aha!
Uh...
Hmm.
That may have been a mistake.
I need to meditate on that one.
Um, okay, here's the thing.
I'll be back.
It's cool, though.
It's fine.
Not a big deal.
We've had worse setbacks.
Gambling is only for the stout of heart.
Not everyone can handle it.
I take the losses with dignity.
This looks like a step room to me.
Okay, money me.
Because I'm not done gambling.
Actually, I do want to find a shop.
This may be the last opportunity we have, especially because we have the memba card, right?
Uh, yeah, you better be a fear to me.
Be a fear to me.
What are you doing, huh?
What are you doing?
Not bad, not bad.
Look at me curving my bullets.
How cool is that?
Hey, come here.
Why are you off, too?
Gonna have a party.
Oh, wait, am I gonna risk this?
This is too risky, I think.
Yeah, I'm actually just not gonna bother.
Fuck him, not for me.
Oh, somehow I didn't get hit there.
That was amazing.
You know what, let's do a curved shot here.
It makes the most sense.
And there it is.
The shop, baby!
Nightlight is pretty good.
I like nightlights, but let's see what they have down below.
What do you have beneath the counter?
Huh?
Broken syringe.
25% chance to gain a random syringe effect for the room.
Okay, that's kind of cool.
But you know what's even more cool?
We can reroll.
We can reroll, baby.
Yeah.
No, Scotland?
Chance to fire a booger.
Oh, the booger is really good.
We're gonna take the booger.
We don't know what...
30...
Why is everything so expensive?
30 for that one.
Jesus.
It may actually be really good, but I don't know.
Let's take this.
Okay, we're gonna maybe reroll again.
Let me see here.
Do I want nightlight?
Slows, enemies, and projectiles.
Oh, I feel like I need that.
The other one was...
Oh, but I can't buy that.
But if I...
I can...
Let me do this.
Three attempts.
Shit.
Okay.
I can blow it up.
Golden horseshoe, chance for the...
There's no treasure room.
Where'd you come from?
Where'd those come from?
What the frick?
Weird.
Okay.
I'm taking this.
Oh, yeah, I like...
We have fear, and we have lights, and we have powers.
We are amazing right now.
And if we get more money, we will get even more amazing.
In fact, I will destroy this poop to get money.
Money for me.
Let me go north.
The flashlight makes me feel so safe as well.
Blow that guy up.
We're going to look for secrets, too.
More range is good!
We like that.
Why does underwear give me range, though?
That's what I want to know.
Oh, wait a minute.
Look at that one.
Do I want to pick it up, though?
I think I do.
But not yet.
Doubles, Isaac, Spombs.
I love that.
Definitely do that.
Hey, come here.
That's right.
The nightlight.
It's going to mess you up.
The boss is here.
This is going to be Mom, right?
We can just go in there and Bible her.
And she's done.
Let's do it.
Oh, are you ready for this one, baby?
That's wonderful.
Wow.
Wait, I can't go back.
Oh, shit.
I should have taken the eternal heart.
Fuck.
Oh, well.
Give me something good here, though.
I see you there.
Uh, rotten baby.
Or striking an enemy from behind you.
Oh, bleed effect.
I mean, ah, that's not too bad.
Rotten baby, though.
Here's the thing.
If I take both of these, I'm actually going to activate my ultimate form.
So do I want to do that or do I want to?
I'm taking both, baby.
Ultimate for me.
But I'm so low on hearts now.
Like, this is scary.
Wait, can I really not go back?
I need to have, like, a teleport card.
Imagine.
That's one way to do it.
Back to the shop room or something, you know?
Um, I can't blow this up either, right?
Shit.
Fine.
Okay.
It's the womb.
A scary place to be when you don't have a lot of HP.
But at least we have the damage now again.
That's going to be massive.
Do I want to do this?
Two chests?
I think so.
Oh, my damage is pretty damn good here.
Hell yeah.
Where are you going?
What's that?
I don't know what that is.
I've had it before.
It's a chicken, right?
Look at the boogers!
Black boogers!
Um, okay.
Squeezy.
Tears.
Oh, that is so big!
That's huge!
I'm so glad I went in here!
And let's not forget there's a battery in there, too, if you want to fly in one of these rooms.
Like this one!
Is it worth it, though, for two bombs?
I think not.
Actually, we can walk over.
We cannot alive.
What do you want, sir?
Oh, oh, oh.
Let me slow you down, actually.
You like my nightlight?
Play this old chest to spawn with...
No, thanks!
I hate that item.
It's like, hey, let me make my chest worse.
Why?
At least I think so.
Maybe I'm totally wrong.
I mean, it is...
I mean, it's an upgrade.
I guess if you don't have any keys, right?
Then it's good.
Hey!
Okay, there we go.
I'm actually going to start bombing all the rocks I see.
Because I'm not sure whether or not there are tinted rocks in this floor.
And I kind of want to get that confirmed or not, you know?
Son, what are you doing?
Blood...
Oh!
That can come in handy!
We're going to keep that.
All right, go!
Okay, we're fine.
Thank God for the fear effect.
Again!
That's the third door that's opening!
Take some coins, man.
More, more, more.
The fool!
Okay.
See, that's the card I should have had just before.
I could have probably gone back with that.
Rotten meat!
There we go.
And then we can do this.
The temperance is coming into play here.
Uh, give me that.
Takes a full heart!
Okay, good to know.
Beautiful.
Get nightlighted, nerd.
Let's just go in here.
I have a good feeling about this.
I'm gonna Bible this sucker.
You like the Bible?
You hate the Bible.
Actually, you love the Bible.
Dude, the boogers are so good.
Nice!
Cheers, one health.
Oh, that's fantastic.
We like that.
We like it.
Then we go back, because we can donate.
Let's go through here.
There we go.
More of a horrible night to have a disease.
Oh, what?
Oh, I messed it up.
Shit.
I want to go back and find more stuff.
We're not done.
Be still.
My beating heart.
Huh?
Sure.
Exchange is quantity.
Yeah, that's fine.
Teleport to the starting room.
What is that one?
We don't know what that is.
Switch it back.
I found pills.
Then we have question marks.
Lock down.
Hey!
Switch it back again.
Sets Isaac's health to one red heart.
No.
Three blue flies?
Yes.
Teleport to the starting...
What's this one?
I found pills.
No effect.
Give me that one.
Let's go down here.
Oh, yeah.
Wait, what is that?
That's the one you can throw at enemies.
Holy water!
What other effects?
Shadows upon hitting an enemy.
Yeah, okay.
Great.
That's good.
Dude, am I glad I went back?
This room was crazy.
Absolutely worth it.
Okay.
This way.
Oi, oi, oi.
Oh, I can't believe that happened.
That was actually so bad.
I have to remember, I have lower damage right now, because I haven't donated blood.
I need to do that.
Since we have infinite bombs, we should look for secrets.
In every room.
Blow it all up.
There we go!
Lots of batteries.
I don't like that.
I hate that.
I actually blow up all these rocks.
Okay, it looks like there's an X on this one.
I think that was!
That's a tinted rock right there!
Without the tint.
We're entering a room with half a red heart or less.
Gain a little Steven Familia that fires homing tears.
Dude.
Wait, half a red heart though.
We can't get to half a red heart.
Yes, we can.
We can get to zero.
30% chance when taking damage to spawn a Gemini.
Oh, I like that a lot.
But wait, do I like it more than the nose goblin?
Do I like it more?
Let me think.
We're entering a room with half a red heart or less.
Gain a little Steven Familia.
I mean, I already have good damage.
Yeah, you know...
No, I like this more.
Yeah, I like that more.
Okay, moving on.
None of these look tinted to me.
Not that one either, but I'm going to check anyway.
It was only a matter of time.
What's up, dude?
Thanks.
Let me see.
I don't think any of these contain anything.
Right.
I mean, we can check.
Although, at this point, I'm like 75% sure that there's only two secret rooms.
I look like a cave explorer with the lamp here.
It's so cool.
You know what?
Give me those.
As we'll do it.
And then we go down here.
Let me grab the batteries.
They were in here.
Nice.
Now we're ready for action.
All right, time to move on.
We're done with this floor.
I think we spent enough time here.
Wait, wait.
Let me actually check this room with all these rocks.
I think I see an X.
No, wait.
I see multiple.
That can't be it.
Actually, wait a minute.
Let me check this.
Okay, no.
Yeah.
It was ambiguous.
The other one I saw was like, oh, that's totally an X, you know?
So if I'm not totally convinced, then it's a no-go.
All right.
We're going to go back and grab the batteries now.
And then we're going to move on.
I'm learning a lot from these runs here, where I get to experiment, you know?
Having infinite bombs and all that.
It's really nice.
We got to donate HP, though, first.
This is important.
And wait, we also get a bit of money here.
Careful now.
Nice.
No!
Wait, I...
Oh, portable...
Okay, that's good.
That's good.
Uh, spawn on three coins.
Yeah, I mean...
Hey!
Dude, we're gonna...
Fuck.
Okay.
One coin.
There's a heart somewhere here.
I know I keep saying we're going to move on, but after this, we will.
Trust me.
Oh, I can't get to that heart, though.
Fuck.
But there's a heart in the boss room.
This way.
Dude, I'm so fast.
Shit, I got to get to the Bible without taking damage.
No, not yet.
Not yet.
Get in here, grab that.
Uh, do it again.
One coin.
That's cool.
Okay, let's not fuck this up.
Fuck!
How?
I was perfectly aligned, man.
Ah, it's over.
It's actually over now.
Fuck me, man.
Well, that was a short and very, uh, anti-dramatic...
What's the word?
It's not looking good here.
Oh, shit.
At least we have good damage, huh?
That's our one saving grace here.
We're gonna appear there.
That's cool.
We're done.
Okay, good.
Gimme.
Um...
I need to look for these rocks!
Uh, I don't see an X anywhere.
Let me really look.
Honestly, I'm a little unsure about this here.
Let me just bomb it.
Okay, I guess I was wrong.
Um, let's see here.
Nothing looks...
Actually, maybe that one.
Nope.
Okay, it was wrong.
It was not obvious.
If it's not obvious, it's not it.
That's the rule.
Curve those bullets.
Nice.
I thought it was done gravitating!
It was not done gravitating!
Jesus.
Nice.
The boogers.
MVPs.
Let's look for Xs in Texas.
I don't see any here.
No, no, no.
None of them are obvious.
There are some Xs, but they don't look obvious to me.
Maybe that one.
No, no, no.
Nope.
That one?
No, I'm not convinced.
Yeah, I'm not convinced.
I was not convinced.
Shit, I don't see any.
Too bad.
I have noticed, though, a high frequency of blue hearts spawning from the tinted rocks.
That's why I'm putting so much effort into trying to find them right now.
Also, I don't think we're gonna find more shops, unfortunately.
Curve the shots.
Okay.
Nice.
That looks like an X, doesn't it?
A little bit?
Fuck!
I'm starting to see things that are not there now.
I'm totally gaslighting myself.
Honestly, I'm not even sure I did see an X when I actually did find it.
I think that was pure luck at this point.
And I need you to pop up!
There you go.
Good man.
Um, don't take that.
Don't take that.
Gambling!
I like that.
Um...
This one.
100% that one.
Count.
No.
I don't want that.
See what he sees.
Do what he does.
That seems like an important thing.
Um, where did we write this?
I'm just gonna write it here for now.
See what he sees.
Do what he does.
By the way, I'm just, you know, with no real reason deciding what seems important or not with these messages.
Sunrace on your little face.
Follow the dog!
Okay.
I will.
You're worshipping a sun god.
Pay to win.
Treasure rooms will always contain a reason.
I mean...
Whatever.
There are no more treasure rooms.
We're done with that.
Thank you for yourself.
You're worshipping.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Come on, give me like a heart or something.
A devil in disguise.
Yeah!
Massive!
Hey, another one!
Oh, that was my card from before.
Question authority.
I need more cards like that.
Your soul is hidden deep within the darkness.
Okay.
Go to the...
Always look on the bright side of life.
Oh, I don't want that, actually.
Like, range is good, but it's not that good.
Oh, shit.
Okay, I guess I'm going to blow up some shit now.
You.
Just because the donation machine could come in handy later, maybe.
It will never be forgiven.
Probably not.
Uh-oh, I'm scared of these eyes!
Masterful dodging, if I do say so myself.
I can fly here if I really need to.
Should I?
Should I fly here?
Yeah, we're probably going to get enough battery.
It's cool.
We're chilling.
Nice.
Anything else I want to do in here?
No.
Oh, no.
Okay, okay.
I am scared.
Oh, yeah, lasers!
Fuck, I got hit by something.
France flight?
Wow!
All right.
Four man's...
Oh!
Dude, that's huge!
Four man's Bible, I just found.
An eye.
Oh, there's the boss!
We're totally going to Bible it!
Here we go.
It's Bible time, motherfucker!
Let's see if it works.
Yes!
Okay, we got to dodge this, dodge this.
Nice.
And we get that.
We can even go in here.
Dark...
What is dark bomb?
Familiar that consumes red heart pickups and drops.
We want that!
What's this?
Ouija board?
Oh, that's also good.
Dude, we're taking both!
Oh, shit.
Wait, I'm a little scared though.
I only have...
So, I have three...
I have two empty red hearts and one full red heart.
I'm curious what's going to happen now.
Okay, thank God.
Okay, good.
Let me take this.
Yeah, spectral tears!
We're going to go back now.
Oh, thank God we can go back.
For a second, I was like, can we go back?
Red heart pickups?
We have one.
It's a half though.
Will that count?
Wait, we have a pill?
Hey, not bad.
Come on.
Who bought something for me?
Oh, I think he needs another half.
Oh, okay.
Um, shit.
Where do I get hearts?
Let me think, let me think.
I'm going to go down here.
Oh, oh.
Kill him, kill him.
Good, good, good, good, good.
That's wonderful.
And...
Ah, come on.
Look at the boogers, they're waiting for him.
You're not ready for that, were you now?
I think I see an X.
Guys, that's an X.
It was!
Except I don't remember which one.
Multiple had X's there, so I'm a little unsure.
Wait, what?
Wait, this costs hearts?
Some kind of treasure map?
One additional, that's useless.
Isaac can hold two pills, a future...
Okay.
Every fourth room is slowed.
The slowing is actually pretty good.
Recharges one bar of Isaac's active item each time it takes them.
Ooh, you want...
Oh, wait a minute.
There's also people here.
What should I do?
I'm going to do this.
Take some keys.
What's that?
Lock chests can be opened without using a key.
A paper clip?
Oh, that's funny.
I don't think I want that, though.
I could give this guy...
So if I give him two half red hearts, I can still do this after.
Right?
And that should be okay.
Oh, it took a full one!
It says a half, though!
Fucking liar!
Should I...
Oh, man.
This one seems like it's about finding another item later on.
So maybe this is not good to have now.
I feel like this is important, though.
The broken watch.
Ooh, shit.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
I'm gonna blow you up, son.
Okay.
I have no red hearts now.
This is the danger territory.
I don't think I feel good about this.
Wait, what?
No!
I didn't mean to do that!
I meant to go back!
Fuck!
Oh, no!
Okay, it's fine, it's fine.
Calm down, calm down, calm down, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
It's okay, it's okay.
Just calm yourself.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
We can do this.
Hey, slow down.
Every fourth room, remember?
What pill is that?
Minus one log, yeah, no thanks.
You can keep that to yourself, son.
Where you going?
Oh, yeah, right.
I have spectral tears.
Nice!
We get to see secrets now.
Oh, wait a minute, we're gonna...
Hold on.
Blue heart, come on.
Yeah!
Huge.
Secret discovered, baby.
There's one more!
No!
Uh, actually, yeah, fuck!
We have the item we need!
Bible is all...
Oh, but wait, I need this, actually.
I want the...
I want this not.
I didn't think it was a trinket.
Yeah, boomer for me!
Boomer for me!
No!
What happened to my other black heart?
Did my black heart just walk off-screen?
Did you see that?
One of them went off-screen and never came back.
What a scam!
What the heck, man?
Okay, there's no secrets in here, we know that, because we can see forever.
Uh, this way.
Get him!
Okay, red heart.
Yeah, poop it out, poop it out!
Yeah!
Dude, this is insane!
We need more red hearts.
I love this guy now.
He's my best friend.
Secret discovered.
Oh, god, we've got the enemies.
Wait, what's happening?
There's an enemy, somewhere?
No?
Okay.
No effect.
I don't believe it.
There is an effect, somehow.
Um, what's that?
Teleport to the boss room.
Rent's flight.
I want this.
Want that.
There's no way we can lose this run.
I'm actually in the driver's seat.
There's literally nothing that can fuck this up now.
With all these hearts, like, dude, my damage?
No problem.
Stay away from me.
Okay, what do we have?
Question mark?
That's fine.
You know what?
I was too fast anyway.
We don't give a shit.
Give me this.
Good night, son.
You're gonna die.
Look at this damage!
Take me to the library, baby!
Yes!
Wait, wait, this is...
Wait, plus one health?
Wait a minute now.
For the current room...
Okay, and this one is...
That's gonna take us to 3 out of 3!
Deals instant damage to all...
Dude, I could even...
Dude, I don't even fucking need the Bible.
I swear to God.
Deals instant damage and bookworm?
That means double tears.
Look at this.
Dude, I'm keeping this.
We are gonna walk in there and bomb the shit out of every room.
Good night!
Nice!
Another blue heart, baby!
It doesn't get better than this!
Oh, shit.
Okay, that was...
Okay, you know what?
I'm actually gonna plate-safe.
Fuck this.
Plate-safe.
Give me this.
We did lose a little bit of HP there.
But I am gonna clear.
Oh, wait.
Should I give this guy some money first?
No.
Fuck him.
Oh, wait.
The timer's dis...
I forgot about the speed down.
I should have used it to my advantage.
No, I wasted it.
Wait.
So, this is where it's zero now.
This is gonna count as one.
If I go...
Ah, but that's gonna take my HP, unless I fly.
One.
We're at one now.
Oh, dude.
I'm actually gonna do it.
Yeah.
Two.
Oh, we're done in here.
Yeah, we didn't lose the black card.
That's amazing.
So, now we're at two.
And then we find secret.
There's one more secret room.
That's three.
And then four is gonna be mom, baby.
Look for secrets.
We have eight bombs.
They should be doable.
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
I found both already.
I'm an idiot.
Okay, it's fine.
Actually, I wanna keep...
this.
2.5.
Dude, I'm gonna smack.
I'm gonna smack the boss.
Oh, wait, I don't have charge on this anyway now.
May as well switch it over.
Ah, unless I wanna keep it for later, I can probably come back and switch it.
Wait, what was that one?
Damage, speed, grant's flight.
Okay, that's fine.
Satan!
I need to remember what you do.
Son?
Okay, I need to shoot you, I see.
Dude, look at my damage!
Oh, wait, I don't even have charge on the book.
Yeah, come on then, what you got?
What you got?
I got a nightlight for your ass.
Yeah, you like that?
You like that?
Oh, you ain't nothing?
Oh, oh!
Wait, we're not done, we're not done.
Uh-oh.
I forgot about that last face.
That's on me.
No!
Oh, wait, we did a challenge.
I forgot that was a challenge.
I wonder why it's called Darkness Falls.
There was nothing dark about that run at all.
Oh, well.
Let's do a randomized one.
Hey, it didn't affect our win streak.
That one didn't count.
That was a warm-up.
Now the real game starts.
It's Isaac.
Back to the classics.
Oh yeah, we have this item now.
B-rolls all pedestal items in the room.
Dude, that is fucking crazy.
And we're rich, potentially.
Wait, we have a bomb.
I'll come back in case I need money.
Oh, I look so bare-bones.
I look so naked.
Look at me.
Oh, okay, I guess I need money.
Converter!
Dude, this is the best day ever.
Oh, wait, what's that one?
Diplopia duplicates all pickups.
Oh, both are actually kind of good here.
Obviously, we're gonna go up here and grab the money.
Let's do it here, so we can actually check for secrets at the same time.
Three flies with one scone.
Let's go.
Money!
A bridge!
It's the best day ever.
The best day ever.
It doesn't get better than this.
Holy...
Okay, let me think.
I could also donate.
Wait a minute.
If I use the D6 here...
I wonder if these count as pedestals.
For science!
Oh!
These two do.
What?!
Okay, so...
Oh, so the shop has like two items.
Three tools, or pickups, whatever you want to call them.
What's this?
Charged, baby?
Familiar that occasionally spawns a battery pickup grants a charge to i6 active item or briefly petrifies all enemies in the room.
That is a fantastic combo with the D6.
Oh, wait a minute.
Didn't I just...
Oh yeah, steam sale.
All right.
I could buy another bomb if I needed to.
I'm gonna take this gambling a little bit.
Cool.
Battery.
Okay, I'm happy.
Actually, I could buy the bomb as well.
I'll be back for that in case I need it.
This is a fantastic start.
Holy shit.
We're gonna stay charged forever.
So wait, when did it do that again?
Hmm, like once per room occasionally, or really occasionally?
Like totally random, as we'll find out.
Oh, come on now.
No suspicious rocks.
Everything looks standard.
Up to spec.
Okay, this is getting a little...
The play was actually insane.
Don't tell me there's like a rock in here now.
Okay, there's not good.
That makes me feel better.
Nice and easy.
If we get Devil or Angel, we're gonna totally reroll.
In case we don't like what we see.
Of course.
Wait, what happened?
Oh, we spawned the battery.
Okay.
Yo, I can actually save up these batteries.
Like I can come back and grab them later, you know?
This is the battery run.
Sponsored by Duracell.
Or whatever the company's called.
Nice.
Are we done?
Nope, we're not done.
Now we're done.
Ooh.
Wait, this is actually good.
I'm gonna keep this.
That is a fantastic upgrade.
I'm taking that.
I'm not gonna reroll that.
Bombs, are you kidding me?
Yeah, this is gonna be so much fun.
Fuck yeah.
That's money for me, baby.
All the secrets will be mine.
I'm really slow though.
I need to, you know, up my speed a little bit here.
Yeah.
Okay.
Uh, we only have the boss left.
Now we need pyromaniac.
Pyromaniac would be the icing on the cake.
Yeah.
Now, I have 12 coins.
I will buy these.
Wait, the full...
The em...
What was the empress?
The empress is the one that spawns foot from the sky, right?
I think.
Shit.
It was not.
For a second, I thought it was also the one that teleported me to the boss room.
I forgot what that one was called.
Oh well, whatever.
It's okay.
So we found one secret room.
We're gonna find more though.
I also just like destroying rocks, okay?
Nice.
Wait, what if I reroll in here?
Ah, but this is a pickup.
It's not gonna work, right?
Yeah, I don't think so.
Like, anything that is an item, from, like, one of the pools.
If you think about it like that, you know?
It's gonna work.
That's what I think.
Pickups, not gonna work.
I need more money.
That's cool.
All right, fine.
Ah, I think we're done here.
It's Dingle.
He's gonna get blown up.
It's gonna feel amazing.
Oh man!
Okay, so I can, I can...
Oh, but I...
Wait, Jesus juice.
That's not gonna affect my bombs, I don't think.
I'm gonna reroll.
Yeah!
I like.
Now we grab battery.
Speed is good.
Become a little faster.
I was a little too slow.
Okay, we're done here.
Thank you.
Fully charged.
And that's it.
Moving on.
Very, very solid first floor.
If I get a Seizel today, we're gonna speedrun it.
I'm gonna beat that timer.
Oh yeah, right, I have bombs now.
I forgot that for a second.
Yup!
Wait, they just got petrified.
What did that?
Hmm, I'm not sure.
Why did they get petrified?
Man, come on.
These little spiders are the worst enemies when you have bombs only.
That was beautiful.
Bombs are so powerful, it's crazy.
I got bombs too, baby!
Ah, Mr. Boom.
No, I don't want that.
I say no.
Whoo!
Add copies of the Bible to all item pools.
Yeah, I like it.
I have become faithful on this day.
I choose to believe in all the higher beings.
And in turn, I shall be rewarded.
Okay, no secrets here.
Also, do you mind spawning some batteries, Mr. Battery?
I haven't seen a battery in a while.
Not to be ungrateful or anything, just saying.
Okay, I'm gonna 100% double check my theory about secret rooms behind walls that have objects on them.
That was very badly formulated.
You know what I mean.
I'm gonna brute force that today.
What's that?
Charm of the vampire.
Heals half a red heart for every 13 enemies killed.
I don't like that.
We're gonna reroll and come back.
All right, destroy this.
I mean, it's decent, but I'm being a little...
What do you call it?
Needy or choosy is the word.
Fully recharges the held active item on pickups.
Yeah.
Yeah, we like that.
I'm also gonna buy that blue heart, but not right now.
Mom's contacts.
More range, chance to fire petrifying tears.
Sure, why not?
That's fine.
I like it.
Oh, that's a big battery.
Oh, wait, I could have immediately done it again, actually.
Playing cards.
I don't want to accidentally destroy the machine there.
Good, good, good.
I'll be taking this.
That was a coin as well, but I don't want to accidentally buy the thing below it.
That's for you.
Very nice.
Oh, oh, Bible.
I can't get in there, though.
Oh, no.
I need it.
Actually, I don't.
Wait, I don't want the Bible.
I'm using D6.
Hold on a minute now.
I could try and re-roll this, but then I can't get to it anyway.
Unless I get flight.
Let's come back later and see.
If I get flight somehow with a card or whatever, you know.
Wait, why is my bomb red?
Oh, man, bombs are so good, actually.
I'm getting pretty good at aiming them, too.
Oh,
God.
Okay.
Boss room spotted, though.
We can go do the boss, actually.
We have 100% demon mode right now.
So if we get the demon room...
Ooh, let's do it.
Seagal.
Oh, shit.
Get that out of my face.
Oh, you're petrified, son.
That's just too bad, ain't it?
Uh, wait, I've had this item before.
Why is it not telling me what it is, though?
Little Steven.
Psychic friend.
Fire-swarming tears.
Well, I wanted to go in here.
Uh-oh.
What's that?
A knife or a shovel?
Uh...
I could re-roll, but I don't know what this is.
Hmm.
Fall...
Ooh!
That's good.
No, wait, is it?
Actually, it's not that good.
I mean, black hearts.
Yeah, fuck it.
I mean, yeah.
That's good.
I like it.
What is this one?
Why won't it tell me?
Oh, sacrificial altar.
Sacrifices up to two familiars.
Ooh, I can sacrifice one of them, actually.
One random devil room pedestal.
That's three- Dude, I'm doing this.
Get sacrificed!
Activates a demon form!
That grants damage and spea- Oh, Whore of Babylon!
No way!
Effect is permanently active if Isaac has no red hearts.
Okay.
Damage and- I'm taking that, of course.
Dude, I think I'm gonna take this as well.
I mean, there's no downside to taking it.
Of course, I'm taking it.
Less tears, more damage.
I think that's bad for me.
Tears do have an effect on me.
Yep.
Tears are pretty good, actually.
They allow me to spam bombs faster.
We'll be moving on.
I'm gonna go grab some batteries now.
Dude, the D6 is so good.
I love it.
I'm just being able to say, nah, I want something else.
That's crazy.
Wait,
this is a max battery.
I should have taken that.
Wasted a little battery there.
Let's see if we can't find more items to re-roll on this floor.
That's what I really want to do.
You're gonna die.
Ah, look at that!
Very nice.
Nothing down there, I don't think, but yeah.
Okay, move on.
We got a room on the right and one on the south.
Good.
Puddle of slippery creep.
Not killing it.
We have found one secret room.
That means there's more.
So we gotta find it.
Double check, yeah.
I think I checked up here already, but...
Yeah, I did.
What about down here?
I mean, I'm not leaving until I find this secret room.
Where can it be?
Could be down here, actually.
Dude, come on.
I don't know if that was close enough.
Well, I don't know where to look now.
We can try down here.
Oh, there it is!
This guy wants bombs.
We have that.
Yeah, we can give you a lot.
Take it.
Nice.
Actually, I'm gonna blow up these.
I'm gonna try not to blow him up.
Actually, he's just gonna spawn bombs, right, if I do that.
Come on, something good.
Gimme, gimme, gimme.
One more.
Bastard.
Fine.
All right, moving on.
Man, I wish I could get in there.
All right, let's leave.
Am I forgetting something?
We have the fool.
Battery is full.
I think we're good.
In fact, we are really good.
Look at our HP situation.
That is phenomenal.
This was only the second floor.
Holy shit.
This run is gonna go crazy.
I can tell you that right now.
And we're blind.
Damn.
Wait, how did that guy not die?
Huh?
Oh, okay, there we go.
Got it.
Oh, no, that question marks.
Well, then, I mean...
Book of Belial.
The Bible.
Maybe I'll use that later for something.
But if I take this now, I can see what I get, right?
Shit!
Oh, but I got three out of three now.
Anarchist, cookbook, summon six.
And that one?
The Book of Sin.
Sponsor, rent, pick up...
No, I don't want that.
I'm good.
So I take this now.
Battery.
I could even keep going here.
But I'm not gonna.
Because I already got what I needed from there.
So does this mean I'm shooting two bombs?
Oh, it does mean that.
Dude, that is actually massive.
Sick.
Ah!
Tactical, strategical, surgical.
Yeah, we take that.
Eraser, I don't like it.
So what we're gonna do is this.
Coupon.
What was that one?
Makes one item in the shop or Devil Room 3.
Select it at random.
Ooh.
It's an active though.
Hmm.
Yeah.
I mean, I can leave it here.
No, I can't.
I may as well use it, right?
Give me the bomb.
Give me that.
Careful not to blow up the machine.
Okay, good.
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
I'm down here.
Nice.
All right, then.
Oh, no.
Wow, that was beautiful.
Felt incredible.
The way I handled that professionally or something else.
The double bombs are actually going hard.
And it's gonna go even harder on bosses.
Yeah.
Nice.
Would have loved to have had that on the last floor.
Blackheart!
Two red hearts?
I mean...
Really want to step, but I can't.
I mean, I can, but I'm not gonna.
Oh, no, wait.
It's every second time I use the bomb.
It's two bombs, of course.
It's not every time.
I thought they were just stacked on top of each other or something, you know?
You know, I'm gonna destroy all the mushrooms.
That's where the good stuff is.
Oh, God.
Ooh, we can potentially reroll in here.
So, let me think.
Ah, we don't have battery.
I'll be back.
Need a bit more battery on that.
Man, I don't know what to pick here.
I have one key.
Ah...
Hmm...
Okay.
What is it?
Missing page two?
Evil up?
Wait, is there a missing page one and three or something?
Plus one black heart deals room-wide damage upon taking a hit that reduces Isaac.
Nice.
Very good.
Uh, oh, wait, what's happening?
Uh, guys, are we good?
Technical issues.
What's happening?
Stream cut out?
Oh, fuck, not that again.
No, really?
Oh, okay, okay.
I'm gonna try and keep an eye on it.
Thank you for letting me know, guys.
Shit.
Oh, man, I had this issue a little while ago and now it's sort of back for some reason.
Like, I was clean for a month or so.
Let's see how it goes.
Yeah.
Thank you for letting me know.
I'm gonna try and glance over a bit more to see if you guys are spamming something.
I'm gonna also disable the bot, yes.
Hold on.
Just so people don't get spammed in case this happens again and again and again and again.
Uh, let's see here.
Oh, god, which one is that?
Twitch.
Disable.
The bot is now offline.
No botting today.
Okay, let's keep going.
I am in the zone right now.
I'm sorry about that.
I don't know why my internet is cutting out.
That's weird.
You didn't miss anything important, other than me making amazing plays, of course.
I actually did something pretty amazing, but you missed it, so.
Okay, we're rich again.
Kinda wanna go back to the shop now.
Also, we have found one secret room.
We gotta find more.
Oh, haha!
That's the one that we just had.
Yeah, that was tough to dodge.
That was a tough one there.
Also, I have battery now.
Wait, how am I gonna kill this guy?
Oh, right, bombs can go across.
Okay, good.
Now, I'm gonna go back to the room in the top, right?
And take it.
It's an active, so we don't want it.
D10?
Devolves all enemies in the room into other enemies.
Oh, okay, okay, that's fine.
I don't actually want that.
Okay, so we're gonna reroll now.
Ghost baby.
All right, why not?
I like it.
Very good.
Uh, okay, go up here.
Bomb the shit out of these fools.
All the way bounced between them.
That was beautiful.
Okay, we don't want that one.
We don't care about that one.
Do we have any batteries?
Oh, wait, I got rid of my battery body, didn't I?
Ooh, that's actually kind of bad.
How pro is this?
Come on now, that was pretty good, huh?
Yep.
Thanks.
Oh, yeah, wait, we have this as well.
Oh, there's the question marks again now.
Let me check for rooms here.
Nothing here.
Nothing there.
All right, all right, all right.
Slowly but surely.
It could be here.
Wait, I don't think that was close enough.
Uh, I mean, it's somewhere.
Where the hell could it be?
Unless there is sometimes only one.
I don't think so.
I think it's always two.
Oh, wait, I can take this.
I don't have a trinket.
Maybe in here?
I also have a theory that these narrow rooms cannot contain the secret.
Oh, okay, six, six, six.
Man, I really want to step, but I can't.
I can't step.
That's so sad.
Imagine stepping, though.
And you like bombs?
That is so much damage.
Oh, god.
Yo, nicely dodged.
Actually insane.
Fuck, I don't have battery.
Oh, no.
Dear god.
Would love to have that battery right now.
I miscalculated all of this.
This was a mistake.
We're gonna take this.
PJs.
I feel cozy.
Heals all red hearts and soul hearts.
I mean, kind of want to step now, but nah.
We don't know what they are, anyway.
But I'm gonna take him, of course.
Multidimensional baby.
Yup, buddy.
Follows Isaac's movements.
We have two out of three on conjoined.
Friendly tears that pass through it are doubled and gain increased range and shot speed.
Oh, that was my other familiar tears just now.
Uh, let's do this one.
Oh.
Blood oath, bleed me dry.
What is that?
Oh, that one.
Staps Isaac at the start of each floor.
I mean, honestly, that's good.
Grants bonus damage and speed for the rest of the floor.
The more health sacrificed to this effect, the more...
Oh, okay.
So if I take the last item now, it's kind of gonna nullify that.
But I'm too curious.
We're taking it.
Ocular rift!
That works with my bombs?
It should.
Please tell me it does.
Can I blow this guy out?
Oh, the Hierophant.
Oh my god!
Yes!
Huge!
I mean, we are totally rolling.
I have no red hearts!
How crazy is that?
And I don't know where the secret room is.
Like, how is that real?
Huh?
I don't know.
37 coins, though.
I feel like we missed something in the shop.
You're gonna die.
Oh, uh...
Okay, yeah.
And we gain random effects because we have the mushroom.
Show me what you got in here.
Oh, wait, this one is...
Coupon.
Ah, whatever.
I'm actually gonna donate.
Donate everything.
Nice!
Broke it.
That's perfect.
That's what we like to see.
Making progress there.
This way.
I'm gonna give up.
Maybe there's only one secret room here.
That's fine.
Also, we are perma-hoored now.
The whoring is gonna go wild.
Oh, question mark hearts?
That's funny, but...
Here's what it is.
Batteries?
We like it.
I'm actually gonna save that battery.
That was a beautiful bomb.
Right here, the secret room.
I was kidding.
Shit!
Man, I really want to step.
I also have the Hank man in case I need it.
Mushrooms.
You know I destroy those.
Yes.
No!
Oh, you're right.
I guess most of the pills are shit now because of the false PhD.
What happens if you get both the PhD and the false?
That's interesting, isn't it?
We're just gonna cancel each other out.
Like, what's...
How does that work?
The other phone?
An opportunity to reroll here.
Let's see.
And now we can actually see what it is.
Meatray.
33% chance of converting red heart drops into...
That's gonna take us to 3 out of 3 on Seraphim as well.
I don't know what it does though, but it sounds good.
I'm not rerolling this one.
Oh, I look so cool!
Fucking hell!
Look at that!
In fact, don't I look like the save file?
The one that says the end.
With the crooked horns, the spiral horns.
Look at that!
That is so dope.
Wait, I always shoot two bombs now.
Oh no, not every time.
Huh.
I'm gonna check for secrets though.
This is so cool.
Dude, there's a bunch of mushrooms in here too.
Rainbow, what's it gonna do?
Nobody knows!
It's the biggest mystery in all of Isaac.
Spawns a portal of slippery creep.
No thanks.
Dude, I'm full on hearts.
Look, I can't even take that.
Mistakes were made.
It's fine though, we're chilling.
The present.
I'm actually not sure what that is.
I'm gonna take this.
Mystery gift, wrapped up nice for you.
The gift is consumed to spawn a random pedestal item from the current room's item pool.
Chance to spawn the poop or a lump of coal instead, of course.
But check this out, now we're gonna do this.
Ahoy!
Yeah, we're taking that one.
Is that another...
Allows active items to...
Ooh, yes.
I'll be taking that as well.
Jumbo cables has appeared.
All right, all right.
I'm actually gonna take this battery.
And we're gonna go down here.
We're gonna have a look.
Glass eye.
Voodoo head.
Chewed pen.
I don't like any of those!
Re-roll!
Ooh, mom's bottle of pills.
Meat.
Oh, that's not too great, actually.
Wait, this one didn't change.
Wait a minute.
Where's my d6?
Re-rolls all pedestal items in the room.
I guess that was just unlucky.
Mom's bottle of...
I don't know if I want any of that.
Maybe I'll come back with charge again later.
Yeah, I'll be back.
There's no need to rush it.
No fucking way.
Speeds up everything, spawns a black heart.
You know what?
Why not?
I'm gonna blow this guy up.
Good night.
I'm gonna head in here.
No, I'm not!
We need charge before we get in there.
Charge, charge, charge, charge, charge, charge me!
Okay.
Blow that up.
Gambling.
I don't know if I like gambling.
I'm not a gambler.
Let's go to the arcade, dude!
Fuck yeah.
Actually, I could also take the heart in here.
Yeah.
All right, guys!
Five coins!
Can I turn them into 15 coins?
Lay down your bits right now.
There's also this guy, actually.
What do you want?
Come on.
Give me something.
Off.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait, we have another battery.
There's a battery back here.
Oh, dude, we're gonna re-roll so hard.
You know what, actually?
I don't think I'm gonna re-roll the shop.
Wait, we're flying.
It took me a bit to realize.
I thought it was just, like, a cool effect for a second.
I forgot that we're flying.
That's even better!
Dude!
Oh my...
Like, we can't lose.
This just got even better.
I'm going in here.
Also, where's the battery?
Oh, I found it already, I think.
Oh, no, don't do that.
Come on, now.
We have the boss left, and perhaps a fight room.
Secrets, we have found one of them.
Regrets, I have none.
We shall be looking for it.
Let the great search begin.
I don't think it can be in here, because, look, there's water.
Like, how am I supposed to exit from there?
Carpet, bomb it!
Okay.
Clear!
Nothing.
This one cannot be, I don't think.
Could be here.
Down here, perhaps?
Okay, well, um, hmm.
Am I being dumb?
Hold on, we have one.
We found one secret room.
Let's try this one.
I'm not sure that actually connected, okay.
Ah-ha!
There it is.
We have full charge now.
I'm going to go inside the boss room.
I should have checked my demon meter before I did.
That was a mistake.
Wow, he died fast.
We got underwear.
I shall...
Yeah, why not?
That's fine.
Let me see here.
Guppy's head.
I have the...
Wait, how's that going to work with my bombs?
Yo, that could be pretty damn good.
Or I re-roll.
That...
I need to see how this works.
I'm too curious.
Oh my god.
It's kind of scary, though, because you can blow yourself up easily.
I may have made a mistake.
We're going to get conjoined if I do this.
Oh, shit.
Oh, no.
Oh, we're going to die.
We're going to die from this.
This ain't good.
Wait, hold on.
Time to gamble.
We're going to gamble.
We got to find some more HP.
I think I just lost like six blue hearts, which ain't great.
Wait, why am I so big?
Oh, maybe a mushroom effect.
Mushroom effect.
What do I want?
I think I want to give this guy.
He's going to give me battery.
I just want to have at least over half.
There we go.
Thanks.
Now we give this guy.
Actually, wait, wait.
I made a mistake.
I should have done this one, because I still have the shop room.
Fuck!
I fucked up.
We're going to kill him.
Okay, two coins.
Battery, battery, come on.
One more.
Bastard.
We got to have a coin somewhere.
Oh, wait.
We don't have any money anyway.
So the shop room is actually kind of useless for me.
What am I even talking about?
We're poor.
I just spent it all.
Right.
Moving on.
I'm curious to see how many hearts we have now.
I'm scared of looking.
This could be real bad.
Now it's actually totally fine.
We're chilling with this.
And we're flying, so...
Ah, yeah.
Dead bird.
Hey!
How fitting.
Cool.
I like...
I don't like the eye of the occult that I got.
I'm just going to say that right now.
I think this was a mistake.
I regret taking it.
I'm going to end up killing myself.
Unless I play well, you know?
Okay, that's cool.
I've got two keys.
Absolutely not.
Fuck that noise.
I need shot speed, dude.
I really regret taking eye of the occult.
That actually nerfed me quite a bit.
Okay, good.
We gain battery?
We're rich again?
Wait, what happened there?
How did the bomb get over here?
That's confusing.
Hey, you want bombs?
I got a lot of those!
My friend.
Sad bombs.
Tear blasts plus...
What was that?
Bombs fire 10 shots outward.
Oh, does that work with my active?
Or with my shots?
Oh, it doesn't.
That's too sad.
Oh!
I just lost a lot of HP.
Whoops.
Mistakes were made.
Actually, I wonder if I re-roll in here now.
There's no item, but there's a pedestal.
Confirmed.
Doesn't do anything.
Now we know.
I'm so scared of dying to my own bombs.
Wait, a rare rift just appeared.
You don't see that every day.
Oh, no!
That's so scary to play with this.
Guys, I think we may be in trouble.
Like, Eye of the Occult has actually fucked my run.
It's also cheap.
I gotta buy it.
No.
Wait, actually.
Piggy bank.
What was that one?
Spawns coins when taking damage.
Ah, it's a little too late for that.
I could re-roll this now.
School bag.
Hey!
That's kinda cool.
Can come in handy.
Oof.
Oh, wait!
Yeah.
And then we're gonna pick this up.
Not yet.
Oh, wait, I forgot to check which floor we're on.
If this is Mom, then we're fucked.
But I think I'm just gonna take it.
Yeah, I'll be back and grab the other one when I have money.
Okay, I'm glad I don't have a lot of tears right now, actually.
Shooting too fast with the setup I have right now is scary.
Oh, look!
The Eternal Heart got put on the very leftmost heart.
That's amazing.
It's protected.
Sick.
That's huge.
Very nice.
That was actually clean as hell.
So fast.
Random mushrooms.
Oh, god.
I think we should just go for it.
The adversary.
He's bandaged up.
Holy shit, he died fast.
Not a problem.
Very huge.
Luke- Oh, that's a good one, baby.
That's a really good one.
I- Okay, it's not quite the one I thought it was.
But it's still good.
It's still good.
And we're pretty much done on this floor.
Wait, we have seven coins left?
That means we can buy the other item we had down here.
I'm gonna go for it.
We can even re-roll it.
If we were so inclined.
Down here.
Oh, wait.
That was not a- Okay, I'm actually gonna take it.
Oh, that immediately completes one.
Oh, okay.
I didn't know that was a thing.
I thought I was gonna get two full hearts at the end of the floor.
Now I know.
Good shit.
I guess that makes a lot of sense, too, when you think about it.
Now, we have not found any secrets, which is a disgrace when you have free bombs.
Jesus Christ.
We got money now.
And a lot of it.
Wait, what?
Oh, okay, never mind.
Two of hearts, doubles Isaac's- Nah.
Moms, footsteps, that's actually not bad.
I like that one.
Now, where's the other secret room?
This is what I need.
I think you can even see scorch marks on the floor, where I tried bombing earlier.
Up here.
All right, where could it be?
Let the search begin.
Yeah, I see scorch marks there.
I mean, it could be up in this room, actually.
I'm just too scared of touching it.
Pull it towards me.
Actually, do that instead.
I may just give up on finding the other one.
This one's been checked.
You see all the scorch marks?
Actually, a nice little detail.
I appreciate it.
It could
be up here, perhaps.
Maybe down here.
Did I check these?
Okay.
Okay, so we have an item for 15 here.
The jar!
Save your life!
That's the one that saves red hearts.
Yeah.
I mean, that's pretty good, I guess.
It's okay.
Super magnet.
I'm good.
I like mom's foot.
I think it's time to believe.
The secret room is elusive.
Maybe here.
Actually, I could just walk like this.
No reason to overthink that, right?
Oh!
There we go!
And we got money to give this guy as well.
He's a dirty one, look at that.
Oh, shit!
Yeah, we have two actives!
Right.
Okay, thanks.
I'm fully charged now.
Actually, I'm going to blow you up.
Caulk off.
That was bad.
All right, let's go.
Moving on, finally.
I know I'm being really slow.
I feel like I'm learning a lot, though.
I've learned so many new things in this run, and the last one as well.
Good for the experience.
We have an arcade!
What happened?
Oh, wait, we take damage on each floor.
Right, right.
That's true.
Which one was that?
Was it...
Oh, god.
Ooh, I don't know which one that was.
I need to remember this.
Missing... no.
Fuck.
Which one's doing that?
Here, it's going to be controlled.
That one.
Blood oath.
That's the one.
Okay, then.
Blood oath it is, huh?
That means we're going to do more damage, though.
That's fine with me.
This guy wants keys.
I don't have a lot of those.
So you're going to die.
Whoa.
I could even do this.
Sick.
Oh, why is that dropping so many coins?
Isn't that unusual?
Come on.
Gimme.
Yeah!
Holy shit, this is the best donation machine of all time.
I don't know why it's spawning so many.
Oh, my god.
What the hell the money's coming out of it?
This is actually infinite gambling.
I think I finally found the real infinite gambling.
This is it.
Oh, that's a good one.
Emergency contact.
I like it more than mom's foot.
Because we can keep bosses still with it and then shoot them.
I would like some keys, if you don't mind.
Or even an item.
Maybe you can handle that.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, man.
Infinite gambling has been destroyed.
The dream is dead.
I didn't mean to destroy that, actually.
I wanted to hit the wall behind it.
But it's okay.
More gambling.
Keep gambling.
Actually, this is not going to give me anything.
I'm just going to blow it up.
Less speed.
Yeah, I like that, actually.
I'm too fast anyway.
I'm just going to do this.
Maybe a bit too risky without pyromaniac.
But it is fun.
I need item pedestals.
And I need it now.
Dude, I can make an impenetrable wall with my bombs here.
Look, you can't pass.
Feels really good.
More gambling.
An arrow piercing.
No, I'm going to reroll that.
Deals instant damage to all enemies.
The damage is dead.
No, I don't like that either.
I hate that as well.
These are all shit.
I'll be back for you.
I need keys.
Can you handle that?
Give me some.
Okay.
Sure.
They're really trying to fuel my gambling addiction here, huh?
Whoa.
Secret discovered.
Let me in.
Here we go again, baby.
We ain't done.
The gambling must continue.
I'm going to trigger this guy.
Oh, I didn't even need to do that, dude.
I have so many coins.
I didn't even think.
Forgot I had 99 coins.
Oops.
That rich as fuck.
Imagine what it feels like to have this much money in real life where you're just like, oh, I guess I just spent a bunch of money for no reason.
How crazy of an existence that must be.
Yeah, I like it.
That's a good one.
We're going to maybe donate.
Honestly, I don't think getting ourselves down to one heart and turning into the demon here is actually helping us when we have bombs.
I don't think it does.
But I could be wrong.
But let's do it anyway.
Let's just stay at one heart.
So, so we have...
Yeah, okay.
So 11 points.
Or is that just the mushroom affecting it?
Probably.
I'm going in.
Mom is going to die so hard to these bombs.
It's not even fair.
What's going to happen here?
Wow!
Okay.
Again, this has to be like a guaranteed thing, then.
Like, it's every time.
Wait, let me actually review that.
Taking damage with half or less red hearts will trigger and...
Yo, that's actually good for me.
Allows access to higher stages can be used to open a strange door.
Okay, where is the strange door?
Spirit of the night.
What's that?
Ah, we already have flight.
And this one is very underwhelming.
Actually, it's not.
It's very good.
I like it.
It's actually very good.
I'll be taking that, thank you.
I forgot that I cannot go back on this stage.
I should have cleared the whole thing before I went to the boss.
It happens.
It's okay.
Look at the minimap.
It's shaped like a cross!
I took damage.
And look, we got a shield now because of the polar.
Oh god.
At blue heart, from what?
I'll be taking that.
And a screw, you.
I can...
Oh, oh no.
I can actually maybe reroll that.
I'm not gonna take it yet.
Hello!
Ah, let's see.
Sick!
Ball of tar, chance to fire slowing tears, chance increaseable luck.
Leave a trick.
I like that one actually.
But, maybe I'll come back and reroll again.
Because I'm not super happy with these.
I'll be back for more.
We're not done.
Yeah, I'm stuck in the corner.
It's okay, it's okay.
Thou shalt not pass.
Find secrets.
Okay then.
You!
Holy...
I like that one.
We take the black heart.
The stars...
Ooh, what was that one?
Teleport to the treasure room if there is a planet.
Let's try that.
Is it finally gonna teleport us to...
It's like this room does not exist!
Fuck.
We're fine.
Use diaper.
Chance to get the scatole effect.
Why not?
I like it better than the...
Dude, I just had an idea!
Watch this!
Hold on.
Wait, wait, what?
It's coming, it's coming, it's coming.
We're gonna wait until we get a preferable...
stat distribution from the mushroom, then we're gonna switch it out.
Come on, change.
Why is it not changing?
There we go, so we...
Minus damage.
Everything's zero.
Okay, let's see what happens now.
Is it every time I enter a room?
Let me just double-check that.
Gain a random pass in mushroom effect for the room.
Do I go in here?
I don't even know what I want.
I guess I would want...
Let me see, if I take this now...
Nothing changed.
Oh, I guess everything went to zero there.
Okay, whatever.
Not even sure that works.
Moving on.
Give me that.
Oh, you got me.
Kidding
me.
Holy...
I can re-roll.
If I want to.
Yeah, let's go back and re-roll.
Here we go.
Ooh, a new type of fluid.
Or giant cell.
Sponsor many familiar.
That's actually really good as well, but I'm gonna try this.
Panic equals power.
What?
Increases Isaac's damage for each empty red heart container he currently has.
Oh, cool.
I mean, not the biggest effect on me right now.
I think I'll take this as well.
Yeah.
I'm happy with that.
I gotta look for secrets rooms as well.
That's for you.
Nothing in there, obviously.
Gimme.
Not good.
Mistakes were made.
Okay, well, that's nice.
Finally!
Look, there's a whole new area.
Man.
I'm taking too much damage here.
Way too much damage taken.
Boss?
Uh, you know what?
Yes.
Teratoma.
Wait, that did a lot of damage in itself.
Oh, it was just the first stage of it, I guess.
Pageant boy.
That's really underwhelming.
Wait, I don't have any charges?
I thought I had a full charge on my thing.
What?
I had like a full charge and then some.
Oh well.
Dry baby.
It blocks enemy shots, chance to deal instant room I damage.
I mean, that is great.
I'll take it.
Although at this point we are getting pretty low on hearts here.
It's not, you know, fantastic.
Damn it all.
You gotta play more safe.
Very nice.
Okay, that's useless.
Oh yeah, that was a secret.
I want to find more pedestals.
Oh shit.
Wait, how am I?
How do I do this?
Now we have a full charge.
Dude, I'm too lazy.
I'm gonna move on.
Fuck it.
I really don't want to look all over the map for this.
Need to just check where I'm going.
Oh!
Yeah.
Very good.
It's gonna de-spelled.
Oh wait, why can I enter this again?
I thought that closed off.
I guess it doesn't in the womb then.
Wait a minute, that's...
Ah, no, no, no, no, no.
I know what it is.
It is the...
It's the goat head.
Remain open.
Fuck, I could have gone back and rerolled in there.
Shit.
Good knowledge to have though.
It is the final stage, except it isn't.
Maybe.
Oh!
Every time, dude.
Please don't give me money.
I don't need any more money.
We're done with the moneying.
Okay.
That is way too messy.
I really should play slower.
No reason to be that crazy.
On Bilgal Chords.
You know what?
It's actually good.
I'm very often on low HP, especially now.
I didn't mean to blow that up!
Fuck!
Mistakes were made.
At least we get a little blue heart.
And a secret.
Gamble my life savings, go.
This is a great idea to do.
I mean, what could...
Okay, it can spawn keys and bombs and shit.
Like, it's not exciting.
I want to get the machine that gives me ill omens, you know?
That's the one I really want.
Very huge, finding that.
I'm so glad we can't take damage from Crete as well.
Man, that's too much money in this universe.
That's huge.
Not bad.
And another secret.
Yeah!
Steven?
This guy wants keys.
I got keys for you.
I've never seen this guy before.
Look at him.
He looks like a dirty key maker.
Okay.
Temperance.
Hey, another one.
I didn't mean to actually run into that.
That was a mistake.
Although, I wonder if I have the invincibility shield and I trigger the machine again.
Is that free money?
Not that I need money.
I was just asking questions here, you know?
I have no more keys!
Dude, I looked at my bombs and I thought those were my keys.
Like, I thought I had 34 keys.
This is going bad!
It's not going well!
A huge mistake!
Fuck me.
I mean, that's pretty good.
But is my umbilical better?
I am entering rooms with half a red heart or less right now.
So I'm not gonna pick that up.
Yeah.
That's fine.
Let's just go.
Fuck it.
We're going.
It lives.
Except it doesn't.
It's gonna die super fast.
Good night.
Oh, whoa!
Wait, we don't go up!
We go down.
This time.
We're not gonna forget.
Oh, wait.
That's a good one right there.
That's...
Wait, that's Lord of the Pit?
Wait a minute.
Rance.
No, I don't like that, actually.
I hate these.
Dark bomb.
Consumes.
That's really good.
We take this.
App so fucking lutely.
And then we go back.
And find all the red hearts.
Oh, wait.
There's red hearts in here.
There's red hearts up here.
Grab it!
Come on, bomb!
Yeah?
No?
Why not?
Is it not a guarantee?
Wait, how do I...
How do I scroll down?
I'm pressing tab.
I have too many items.
I can't actually scroll down.
That's crazy.
We gotta find some red hearts.
Nah!
Hey, at least we got a consolation prize.
We're doing a full clear.
Everything must go.
Hey, get out of that.
Okay!
Very nice.
Keys are good.
We're not gonna get hit by this.
We got hit by it.
Insanity.
How does it happen?
We got battery now?
How are you hitting me?
We're losing everything!
It's all going away.
It was a great run.
Shit.
This is really not looking great.
Okay, a blue heart at least.
Hey!
Thank you, bomb!
That's actually huge.
You're helping me right now so much.
Did we find secrets?
We did find them, okay.
No reason to look at them.
Let me see here.
Can we use this re-roller anywhere on this floor?
Oh wait, that's not a way to go.
What does this symbol mean?
Does this work?
Fuck!
It doesn't work.
So I guess trinkets are exempt from that rule.
Oh!
We're going down!
Fuck!
I could have re-rolled this.
We're going down!
We're going down.
Okay.
It's time to destroy.
Satan ain't got shit on me.
He gonna die.
Oh yeah.
You're gonna- One of these weirdly infested flies!
Dude!
It's going horribly!
It's all over!
It's over!
I don't want to die like this!
Not like that!
Oh my god.
At least we got batteries!
Speed run!
Speed running.
Take it all.
Yeah.
Oh, I should have picked it up, actually.
That's fine with me.
We're fine.
This is cool.
We're chilling.
It's okay.
Just calm down.
Look at this guy!
That's a new one!
Open up!
We're gonna find the boss and kill him as fast as possible here.
Look at these demon guys!
Oh, I didn't mean to go back.
Fuck it!
We're going in here, I believe.
Pick it up!
Yeah.
Show me something good!
Goodnight!
Huge.
Actually, we're 99 coins.
We can re-roll a bunch here.
If we need to.
Oh, wow.
Speed and...
You know what?
Yeah.
I'm too fast, anyway.
Give me a key.
How did I take damage?
What did I get hit by?
Dude, there's no way I'm gonna win.
I have too little HP.
Unless I can out damage him.
Also, who's alive in here?
Oh, you.
I see.
Okay.
Now I'm actually a little bit too slow.
I regret taking the...
Niiiiight!
Ah, it's over.
We are done.
Fuck!
Just ended already.
End my life.
Mega DPS time!
Oh, there you are.
I'm gonna fucking die now.
I KILLED MYSELF!
HE'S GONNA FOOT MY STOP!
DON'T DIE, YOU IDIOT!
NO!
WE KILLED THEM, NO!
WE KILLED
THEM!
Fuck this guy, man.
Twice in a row he ruins my day.
I don't believe it.
I don't fucking believe it.
Randomize.
E- Dude, this randomizer is bullshit.
I swear to god it's rigged.
There's just no way I'm getting no... difference in character.
Like, it's the same fucking characters.
Every time.
Oh, wait, that was a key there.
Okay, okay, that's fine.
As long as I can confirm you don't have the green goop inside of your tummy, then I am a happy clam.
I'm poor.
But wait, I have the d6?
Um... I'm still poor, though.
Like, owning a Lamborghini and not having any gas, right?
Sweet.
Ooh, I could actually get in there if I wanted, but I don't want it.
Oh my god.
This room is insane!
Nothing I could have done there.
Wow.
What on earth is this even?
Jesus.
Okay, at least you don't have a laser.
Uh... I'm actually just gonna go in here.
Am I?
I am.
We're going for the ovum.
I'm gonna blight his ass.
You're gonna laser me?
There it comes.
We can't step in the red shit!
Run circles.
Ooh, it's getting very close.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Clean.
Very clean.
I hate this item.
Boom.
That's even worse.
Come on, please be good.
Haha.
Nice.
Oh.
All right.
That's fine.
I'm happy.
No to me.
This guy just jumped into the fire.
Doing me a favor.
No tinted rocks, so we move on.
I don't think we can get enough battery to start re-rolling the treasure room.
But we are getting some money.
In fact, I'm not gonna open that yet in case the treasure room requires a key.
It does not, it seems.
Fucking cornered.
No thanks.
Ooh.
Oh.
That one is fantastic.
Wish I had that last time.
With the amount of bombs I was throwing around.
Okay.
Now I'm gonna grab this.
Sick.
This run is gonna be all about stepping.
We're gonna acquire as many red hearts as possible and we're gonna be stepping up.
You best believe it.
Ultimate steppage.
You've never seen someone step this much.
Arcade, I'm not gonna be tempted.
I look so silly with his hat on.
Oh my god.
Very nice.
Good start.
Now this is... So we're gonna drag them into the corner so I can run.
No, this guy's... Yeah, we made it.
Okay.
Kill him!
Uh-oh.
Run!
I'm happy that they're slow.
That was really good.
And I need a key.
Point.
For you.
Look at the precision on these shots.
The hagalas, you know what?
Why not?
Oh man, I need more keys.
Oh no.
Get the little guys out of here.
Oh my god.
No!
Oh.
He exploded even.
What was that?
I actually have terrible DPS.
Okay, we got a key.
The question is, am I gonna spend my re-roll on this room or not?
Pupula duplex.
Spectral tears increases tear sight.
Oh, I mean, that's a good one.
I don't mind not re-rolling that.
So now we're gonna need another key.
At least this
guy doesn't fart.
Okay.
Not going in there.
Dude, I have a feeling right here.
Yes.
Okay, it's gotta be here then.
I don't think so, actually.
There's a jar in the way.
Here.
Uh-oh.
Not the red flames!
I knew I was gonna get hit by that.
That
was terrible.
Fucking red flames are my worst enemies.
No!
Guys, the stepping dreams are so over.
No stepping with this guy.
At least he has a lot of damage.
That's something, actually.
Almost five damage?
That's actually kinda... kinda good, isn't it?
Now, of course, the HP situation.
What?
Dude, that's great for me.
I still have decent damage.
I don't know why they're going crazy like that, but yeah.
I think I'm happy with it.
It may have been a mistake, I'm not sure.
We're gonna try and find more damage, though.
Like, pure damage.
Yeah, the randomized flight patterns I'm not a big fan of.
Well, that's useless.
I don't want any of this.
Don't mess it up now.
This is easy.
Good.
Oh my god.
That was a little too close.
Okay, I've gotten plenty of practice, though, with BB.
To not taking damage, so this should be a walk in the park, right?
Compared to that.
I'm a different man nowadays than I was the last time I played Judas.
I'm a change.
I'm gonna activate my book and shove it up his ass.
666.
Oh my god.
I'm so scared of getting hit by anything.
Alright, alright, that's cool.
We got him, we got him.
No problem.
Please be HP.
Okay, that works.
I'm happy with that.
I can live with it.
Not bad.
And I'm just gonna move on, I think.
Yeah.
Good start.
Massive start.
Not the ma- Oh.
Wow.
You ever seen something like that?
That was crazy.
Daddy long legs.
Oh, that guy's pretty good.
I like that one.
Daddy's love.
I'm gonna meet that dad today.
I'm gonna be out in the yard having barbecue.
We're gonna have a fast internet connection.
He's gonna have a mustache, I hope.
That really is terrible.
I'm not sure I made the right decision grabbing this attack speed thingy.
Good.
These guys are not jumping though.
These are standard jumps.
Oh, uh, okay.
I'm going in.
We activate the book, shove it in his mouth.
He's blue.
Oh my god, homing tears.
Don't you dare.
Nice, and a blue heart.
Yo.
Wait, no, that's attack speed.
Enough of that.
Okay, I'm gonna take a peek here, but I'm not actually gonna- Yeah, fuck this place.
Dude, we are going for angels.
I hereby announce angels are in effect.
I repeat, angels are in effect.
Run!
Wait, labyrinth is messing with my mind.
Lovely.
Oh, no thanks.
We're done.
Wait, we have a shop actually.
We're not done.
Okay, so I can't afford that.
I'll take a key.
Who knows whether or not I'm gonna get fucked next floor, you know, not having a key.
I think that was a worthwhile investment.
Wait,
why can I still enter here?
Is it the book or what?
See, this time I don't have that item that makes this stay.
So why am I still able to do that?
Weird.
Oh, you guys are actually- I thought you were statues.
Come on.
Oh my god, that was super close.
How am I surviving these encounters?
The foot could backstab me here.
I think we're safe.
I'm glad I bought that key.
Oh, absolutely atrocious.
Are you gonna- Okay, thank you.
I really need like one more red heart.
There's a lot of things I need.
But that is on the top of the list.
No way.
So lucky.
Love when that happens.
Let's go up here.
Don't get hit by the red fire.
Piggy bank.
Oh, I don't have enough for that.
I
want coins.
I'm not gonna give you coins.
I'm saving them for a special and rainy day.
Okay.
I'm gonna go in there.
Man, really?
Dude, how about some damage?
Why is it every time I get this freaking item that gives me insane amount of tears, I just keep getting more and more tears?
It's never damage I find afterwards, you know?
Never.
Have you noticed that?
But I mean, at some point, I mean, this is DPS, right?
Man, don't tempt me with these freaking deals when I don't want them.
I could take them.
This would boost my DPS if I do it right.
Wait, this will actually give me a lot of damage.
But I'm gonna be at one blue heart.
Oh, dude.
I think I'm gonna do it.
No, it's too risky, man.
I'm gonna fucking die.
I'm gonna go down here and get hit by a fire and die.
Oh, shit.
Nah, I'm playing it safe.
And I do have the book, you know, for rainy days.
See?
Let's see if I would have died or not.
It would have been bad, you know?
Yeah, I would have been at one half blue heart right now and I would have hated my life.
Yeah, and there I would have died.
Shit.
I'm in danger.
I'm in so much danger.
This room is some bullshit.
Come on, please deactivate.
Oh, thank God they deactivated.
I'm gonna damage.
I don't trust.
Give me a good character, please.
Okay, that's cool.
I haven't had her in a while.
Nice.
This is the step character, by the way.
Spider-by, chance to fire slowing.
Sure.
We're totally gonna step on this character, dude.
Don't you?
Yeah, okay.
I had a feeling.
So when these guys are colored in any way, the farts are dangerous.
Always.
Okay, I'm scared.
Whoa!
Brother man!
Okay,
there we go.
Oh, no.
It's one of the worst rooms ever because they're just annoying.
I even got hit from that.
What a tragedy.
Terrible.
Let's go up here.
Nice.
Okay, we can go in here now, but I'm not gonna be able to buy anything.
Whoa!
What the fuck is this?
Hello?
What's happening?
Who are you guys?
Why is this happening?
Huh.
Two coins.
And a bomb.
Steam sale.
Blue map!
Reveal secret rooms.
That is really nice.
Oh, I really want to buy that.
Can we get the money for it?
We have zero luck.
It's kind of rough on this character.
I don't know what it is.
You should feel slow and clunky.
Yeah, why not?
It's Hadoop.
I just want to step so bad.
Give me an opportunity.
Yeah, this is like the tame version of the boss.
Sometimes he's much more scary.
Like more aggressive and stuff.
This one is not the scary one.
Again.
I'm not gonna pick them up yet.
Just in case I find a step room.
I'm actually gonna get one of these.
Okay!
Very nice.
Can we get lucky again?
I have a feeling.
Come on.
Okay, that's pretty good too.
I like it.
Massive.
Totally worth.
With ten coins, we can buy... we can buy a blue heart.
But I'm sure I want that.
Let's check first of all if there is a step room.
Because if there isn't, then it doesn't matter.
Oh, there it is!
Holy shit!
Lock smiles upon me.
Did you see that crap?
He pushed his friend in front of my path.
In fact, he pushed him right into me.
Let's see here.
One.
Two.
That's a coin.
Three is blessed.
I didn't really think this through, did I?
We don't have enough.
I'm gonna step with my blue hearts.
That's right.
I'm doing it.
I'm cashing in.
I'm taking the money out of my kit's savings account.
And I'm gonna spend it at the casino.
Trust it'll be good.
Here we go.
It's fine.
Well, you know, I feel double blessed now.
That's surely a good sign, right?
This was worth it.
It's also half a red heart.
Damn.
I mean, we can step one more time, actually.
We can do one more.
One more.
I'm going for it.
I'm actually at this point where I go to the doctor's office and I sell off my blood for drugs and gambling money.
Like, I'm emptying half of my body of blood.
The big payout is coming.
Here we go.
Okay, that... You know what?
I would say it wasn't not worth it, but it also wasn't worth it.
You know what I mean?
You have to factor in the excitement of the gamble.
That alone was worth it.
Also, I have 14 coins.
We're not done.
Oh, I keep going.
We're gonna keep stepping.
You thought I was done?
Nuh-uh.
The step is real.
Surely this will be the payout.
Here we go.
Aha!
Uh, yeah, okay.
I mean, that's cool.
Half a red heart!
Well, this is gonna be interesting.
I may be in danger here.
I'll be real with you.
Okay.
I don't even know his moves.
Okay, he's doing that.
Aha!
It was okay.
It's just, you know, part of the process.
Okay.
No!
We were so close!
Oh, man.
Alright, at least we're gonna get the opportunity to unlock a new character now.
If I can do this without reviving, we're gonna unlock something new.
And it's gonna be good.
And also, I have decided in this run I will not make bad decisions.
Simply because this one is important.
It is forbidden to make bad decisions.
I'm gonna make the most level-headed decisions you have ever seen.
Okay.
Lots of poop.
Oh, wait, we have a pill.
Oh!
Too bad it was full health.
We could have saved that.
I think I just pushed that guy into the flame.
Okay.
Yep, dodged that.
Isn't that weird that he just dropped the key like that?
I feel like I never see that.
Like you get a reward for doing the room, right?
But just killing an enemy like that, he drops a key?
I feel like that's unheard of.
Let's go window shopping.
You know what?
The jar is actually not bad.
It's only ten.
Maybe I'll be able to afford that.
I wouldn't mind that at all.
This could also be a step run.
But, I mean, no bad decisions, right?
So we'll have to say about that.
I feel like a step run is inherently, you know, a bad decision.
Okay.
Fusing tears, respectable.
We can make some plays with that one, for sure.
But that's really much... that's it for this floor.
Unless we want to look for secret rooms.
Honestly, there's one right here.
There would be one right there if I had anything to say about it.
But I don't.
Okay, this guy is actually kind of tough.
Because he does that.
Oi, oi, oi!
Man, he came at me fast.
Whoa, get out of there.
Jesus.
Wow.
Man, this is one of the hardest bosses.
Change my mind.
Fuck!
No, you gotta be fucking kidding me.
Okay, wait, we gained a bunch of damage, though.
Right, so when he dies, he actually gains damage.
Alright, moving on.
So we had 6.2, we had 3.5 before.
So what is that?
That's like 70% more damage or so, approximately?
Okay.
Wait, why are we at 4.43 now?
We should be at 3.5.
Pedals up each time, there's nothing here.
Maybe there's like... I don't know.
That's actually kind of weird.
Someone's Monstro to slam down?
That's pretty good.
A decent active.
Hard to find these days.
Oh, slam it.
Put them in the slammer.
Wait, I thought I had Spectral Tears.
Why are they not going through rocks?
Maybe I misunderstand what Spectral Tears means.
Okay, they go through enemies but not through rocks.
I really thought that's what Spectral Tears meant.
Oh god.
These guys are going to speed up.
No!
Okay.
It may actually be worth it to grab that.
Just because one heart is pushing it.
Playing it safe.
I cannot hit.
That was a fun duel.
Oh no, the Jittery guys!
Now we can heal up again.
This is one of the good decisions.
I'm also using my active at any time it's ready and stuff.
That is also a good decision.
Only good decisions today.
Three keys, that means we're going for this chest because it's probably better.
Apple of Sodom.
Chance to convert a red heart into blue spot.
Oh, I don't like that.
That's terrible.
No, thanks.
Garbage items.
This one is good though.
Treasure room has been found.
So actually, you know what?
Yeah, why not?
I almost considered just going straight for the boss and ignoring this room.
Because that could be classified as a good move.
Thing is though, I could get in here.
No, see, that's a terrible decision.
That's too risky.
I'm at low HP.
Let's not make bad decisions.
That's what past me would have done.
This is the new me.
Yeah, run into the poop.
That's good.
Dude, what is this predictive movement?
How do you know?
It's like he knew I was going to turn.
He knew I was going to go down the street and turn quarter.
Okay.
Yeah, that's massive.
Let's go, man.
Huge.
Three hearts, baby.
We're going to use the tooth in here.
Boink!
Aha!
It missed.
Unfortunate.
Is it just me or is my damage garbage?
Like, I have... Huh?
They can't die.
That took ten years.
Actually, now that I think about it, since I already failed this challenge of unlocking the character, if I could go super optimal with this character, I could actually die, get the damage up, get like three damage or so, before I go to the boss.
Because I'm going to get a new revive next floor anyway.
Right?
So just fucking do it.
Oh, wait.
It's not even for the room.
It's actually for the entire floor, you gain it.
So maybe I'm okay with dying.
I mean, I'm not going to, you know, just kill myself, but...
Maybe I'll make more risky places, what I'm saying.
Like, for example, going in here.
We ruined the challenge anyway.
Actually, there is one downside to doing this.
If I actually fail the boss, I can't come back, right?
That's the big problem.
Yeah, maybe it's not a good idea, actually.
Okay, these guys are kind of tough.
Oi!
Die!
Smashed.
It's pretty much like a panic button for me, the space bar.
Like, oh, I don't know what's happening.
Just press it.
Yeah, why not?
This may come back to bite me in the ass.
I'm going to find a treasure room now that requires a key, and I'm never going to find a key again.
You'll see.
I'm kind of boxed in here.
It's going to jump towards me now.
Okay, well, it's fine.
Seven damage now, yeah.
Actually, it's fine, yeah.
I don't mind dying.
Wait, we lost a heart!
We can't die.
Oh, this is the problem with that.
Yeah, okay.
Of course.
I regret everything.
Well, not that I died on purpose there, but you know.
Hey!
Look at this here.
Wow.
And speed?
Nice.
Get smashed.
Oh, I could...
Wait, I can't enter yet.
Do we have enemies in here?
Oh, massive.
Ah, hey guys.
How's the crack of lacking?
Are they going to get hit by that?
Ah, what?
They're immune to the spiky boys?
I don't like that.
I feel like they should take damage from that.
What's that?
Mongo, baby.
Fires tears at Isaac's base tier rate.
Copies the tier effects of other familiars.
So if we get a little brimstone, we're going to have two brimstones.
That's what that is saying.
Let's try and find one.
Ah, I'm in danger!
Shit!
That was badly played.
I should have taken out the guys on the left first, for sure.
Oh, that's actually big.
Not grabbing that.
Probably should have gone to the shop first, but it's okay.
Polycephalus!
Get smashed by Monstro!
Monstro's with me now, buddy.
Oh, massive!
That was massive!
Are we going to trade that away now for something?
What the hell is that one?
We got a new one!
Okay, let me see.
Seven seals!
Little harbingers!
Grant's a wandering harbinger familiar that spawns locusts and deals contact damage.
It shifts form every ten seconds.
Each form spawns locusts with a unique trait.
So, is my guy going to copy that, then?
The Mongo?
Or what?
Oh, I guess the dude here doesn't have a tier attack.
He's just going to sit on his horse and horse around, I guess.
I didn't go to the shop!
What the fuck, man?
My brain is getting turned into mush right now, unfortunately.
Yeah, it's not good.
So, okay, hold on a minute, we have 5.19 damage.
I don't understand this.
Am I actually gaining, like, a permanent damage up?
Between floors?
Or this character?
Or what?
Oh, I have a green fly now.
Oh, yeah, he shifts into different forms.
Because there's no other items that affect my damage right now.
But there's something going on with...
with Lazarus.
I'm not complaining, I like it!
More damage makes me happy.
Let's go this way.
Okay, Monstro, I need you.
Smash my foes.
Oi!
Where did you jump to?
Oh, for a second I thought Monstro was an enemy.
And he was going to fall down on me when he jumped up.
That messed with me a little bit.
Kill him.
Confusion was real there.
I love the atmosphere in this type of level here, with the water.
I could gamble, or I could not.
I'm going to stay for the shot.
Oh, there you are.
Good, I need more range.
My range is terrible.
A chance to spawn a red heart when damaged.
Taking damage when the guys get gushed.
Blood tears.
Every 20 seconds while bleeding.
Loose.
Running out of red hearts or healing red hearts will stop the bleeding.
Dude, I don't like that.
Then again.
Taking...
No.
That sounds absolutely horrible.
Sounds like a downgrade.
Unless I'm reading that well.
Not good for me.
Maybe for the horror it would be good.
See, that was one of those decisions that were smart, I think.
I looked at it and I said, you know what, let's not pick it up.
I like what we've got going on, let's not ruin it.
These guys are tough.
Actually, as long as you stay on the move, they're not that hard to deal with.
Chub.
Monstro!
Nice.
I think I actually misplayed that.
I should have used it after I killed his little minions.
Just so I guarantee that it hits him and not his minions.
Unfortunately, I lost a black heart, so...
Yeah, nice.
I love getting these HPs.
Let's go to the shop.
This time I'm not forgetting.
Although I was close to forgetting.
I'll admit that.
No, it's not a real shop, it's fake!
I hate it.
What am I going to spend all my money on, then?
Ah!
The arcade, of course!
That's what you should point your money on.
Who will I give money to, though?
I think this guy.
He's been good to me in the past.
That's very nice, thank you.
Actually, let's just alternate here.
Bombs?
Very good.
I'm actually going to bomb this.
Dude, this is totally worth...
Whoa!
More health!
Oh my god, this couldn't be better.
Can we step?
Dude, we can step.
I'm totally going to step.
Maybe I'll even step myself to death!
We're going to get all the hearts.
Scatole!
Hey!
This room was so worth it.
I'm so glad I went back here.
Wow.
Okay, wait, wait.
Remember when I talked about bad decisions?
Actually, we do have a lot of hearts on the map.
This is a good decision.
We step.
I have decided.
Shit!
So far, it has not been worth it.
Okay, well, three coins.
I mean, I think that was worth it.
Yeah, that was good.
Now we grab some hearts.
And we'll four...
We're full on hearts.
Now we move on.
Easy coins.
These guys...
Oh wait, Scatole is going to be so good against these.
Look at that one.
Yes.
I will take it.
Mom!
This room is actually killer.
It is so scary.
Okay, we made it.
I can go step again.
No, that's not a step room.
That is a...
curse room.
No!
Oh, fuck off!
Stupid ass bomb!
Wow!
He nearly killed me.
Huge.
Come on, RNG, fix my mistakes.
Oh yeah.
Nice.
Let's see here.
I think I want to take the gift.
Steam sale!
I can almost buy...
Oh, what do I want?
I guess this one.
Yep.
Solid so far.
Spawns a blood donation machine.
Maybe.
Adversary.
I should have seen that coming.
Thank you.
Oh, I love these items.
These are so good.
Tears is all so much needed right now, so that's wonderful.
Although we haven't found a treasure room.
Of course we got to find that.
Money, though.
Probably focus on...
this first.
Joy!
Sweet.
Blue hearts, come on.
Jage!
No, no, no, no, no, no.
You cannot be jumping up on the...
One second, guys.
One second, I'm just going to quickly...
quickly give her a snack.
Just serves a snack.
I'll be right back.
There we go.
Sorry.
She was way too cute.
I had to give her a snack.
Look at that one!
It's a new item, Super Ball.
She has to fire a bouncing tear, increases with luck.
I mean, I don't have any luck.
Do I really want that?
I think I do want that, actually.
I have enough keys as it is.
Okay.
Envy.
I mean, that was pretty nice.
Actually, this takes me ten years to kill.
Boss is dead already.
What am I looking for?
Treasure room.
Oh, shit.
Wow, I don't know how I did that.
Oh, man, nothing?
That's unlucky.
Dude, this guy on the horse is actually pretty damn good.
My reflection.
Ah, wait, this is the one that does this weird thing.
Where my tears go weirdly, right?
But six range, so much damage.
Oh, wait.
Oh!
The last time I had this was on Azazel, I think.
And things looked very different on Azazel.
Wait, what happened there?
Jira!
And Battery.
Wait, how am I getting out?
Oh, I see, I see.
I don't see.
Don't pick up the card.
Tough room.
I think we're ready to go.
I'm not going to explore the last room there.
I'm fine.
And now I know how to use the Jira probably.
Or properly.
We're going to fill up a room with a bunch of blue hearts or something, and then we're going to multiplicite.
I don't know why I'm suddenly sounding Scottish or whatever.
I really need some food, actually.
I can feel that my mental faculties are degrading right now.
No!
What am I doing?
What a waste.
Massive blunder.
What is that one?
Spillunker Hat reveals the map up to two rooms away.
Reveals icons for nearby special rooms on the map and prevents damage from falling protectors?
Why not?
Oh, it even...
Fuck yeah, it even shows the secret rooms.
I gave him my ultimate key!
Ah, well.
I didn't mean to do that.
I didn't even realize I could do that, but I guess I could.
Shit.
I guess I'm using this now.
I feel like I need to use it just to make that feel like I didn't waste my everything, you know?
I mean, the damage is starting to be pretty good.
Oh, yeah.
Golden Horseshoe.
That's a really good one.
That's massive.
Now we're gonna go this way.
Yeah, let's get in here.
And a secret at the very end.
Beautiful.
Dude, this hat is gonna be so valuable as we go on.
I can donate a little bit.
That's good enough.
Actually, I'm gonna blow them both up.
I won't be coming back.
Oh, wrapped that one.
And I think we're done, right?
No, a shop.
Find a shop.
And of course, find out where the boss is.
How did this item work again?
Consumes one key to launch a sharpened key in the direction of my choice.
The key damage and pierce's enemies can also open the first lock or destroy the first obstacle.
That is kind of important.
Oh.
Definitely killing those first.
It's such a liberating feeling knowing that there's no secrets that I cannot find, you know?
Spectral tears are especially good against those guys.
Very nice.
And just in time for the...
No, it's not even a real shop.
Why is the game doing this to me?
I just want to spend my money.
Don't give me money.
I need to spend it.
It's too much.
Cruel fate here.
That's for you.
Wait, that's...
Wait a minute.
Uh...
Did that just spawn this weird triangle?
Because I did the key?
Huh?
We need to investigate.
Keeps the door open.
Okay, let's just move on.
I'm gonna key you!
Oh, shit.
That's for you.
Yeah, you like that?
Oi, that was close.
Mistakes were made.
Nice.
Good, good, good.
Solid.
And then we get this item.
Okay.
Bring him the photo.
Him.
Satan?
Isaac?
Who else do we know of?
Oh, yeah, right.
They don't go through stones.
That was a bit too risky.
Yo, nice!
I mean, we would have found this anyway, but, you know.
Blow him up.
Always makes me feel better.
Well, I'm kind of trapped in here.
No, not really.
It is really dark in here.
Barely see a thing.
Oh, god.
The mirror is sort of pushing these bombs back towards me.
Okay, oh, oh, oh, oh.
And we have a secret room here.
Is it here?
What?
No.
Okay, hello?
Where the fuck is this thing?
Okay, well that, I feel like...
Whoa, look at this room.
Whoa.
Why does it look like this?
Well, that was not worth it at all.
That was terrible.
Don't kill me.
Look at the way they sort of turn.
Dude, I think it's actually over.
I didn't even realize we were this low.
This is rough.
Right here.
I'm in danger.
Yeah.
So we get the extra damage.
Three hearts now.
Oh, that's rough.
Whoa, these guys are mega fast.
Stay away from me.
Egg, lament, sling.
Okay, fine.
But what about healing?
Healing, maybe?
Weird room.
Gimme that.
Show.
I could barely see them.
Scary.
Gimme.
We're also gonna blow this up.
Please be healing.
Yeah, that is fantastic.
Just what I needed.
Now I wasted this.
You know, I could have duplicated that, actually.
But...
I mean, that's just assuming that I'll take damage later on.
Dude, I gotta find someone that will take my money.
This is getting to be a real ridiculous problem.
Sitting on all this capitalism.
Or capital.
Too much capitalism.
And where's the boss at?
He's gotta be here.
Nope.
Sixty-six dollars.
In my account.
Kill him fast.
Nice.
Dude, my damage is pretty good.
Good damage here.
And here's the boss.
Ooh, let's pill it.
Okay, that's fine.
Okay.
This should be not ellipse, but the one before that.
The bloat.
I'm gonna key you.
Wow, he actually hit me first.
Yeah, you like keys?
Man, those keys did a lot of damage.
Wow.
More range is actually not bad.
Wait, we have nineteen range?
Okay.
Grabbing this heart, though.
Wait, no treasure room found yet.
Wait, is there even a treasure room on the womb?
Maybe I've had that upside down.
I need to actually test this.
Because a lot of stuff doesn't exist in the womb.
Also, I just got hit for no reason.
Dammit.
Gimme that.
I mean, yeah, it looks like there's no treasure room.
Ha!
Well, well, well.
Look at that.
I'm actually kind of glad there's no devils here.
I would just be sad looking at the lovely deals I could have made, but, you know.
I don't... I can't afford it with my current HP pool.
Fucking shitty room.
All these batteries.
And wake up!
Nice.
Uh-oh.
What?
Bro.
Oh, he died.
He died.
Okay.
I should have duplicated that, I think.
Or maybe I shouldn't have.
I'm not sure.
Also, can I un-shoot this?
Okay, nice.
Shoot it!
I don't trust, like... Oh, healing, nice.
Healing is fake.
Like, that sounds like I'm taking damage.
That sound effect, I feel like this should really change that.
It's confusing.
My job there is done.
Oh, God.
Jesus.
It's not even that bad, actually.
That looked way worse than it was.
Okay.
As soon as I find the boss, I'm gonna go for it.
No dilly-dallying.
Mom, I'm not in the mood for this.
Don't shoot there.
There's three hands!
Yeah!
Okay, we got him.
Holy shit.
Dead end.
Good.
Key for you.
I don't want to step on that.
Blade safe.
For sure, Mom.
Oh, there's actually a secret back there.
I'm gonna go back.
There could be a game-changing item in there.
Who knows?
Boink!
Let's see if it's game-changing or not.
Well, more money, I guess.
Blow it up.
We gained some demon meter there.
Oh, no way.
No way!
I can't believe it.
Is this the end?
Ah!
I'm gonna blow that up.
No!
Should I duplicate it?
Nah, that's not worth it.
Not for half a heart.
Shit.
Oh, man.
There is another secret somewhere.
We haven't seen it yet.
It's probably in here, isn't it?
Key for you!
I have one key left.
I shouldn't be using them as, you know, freely as I am.
Time to save on keys.
Kill him.
Absolutely not.
Watch for projectiles.
Whew.
Secret room spotted.
Not the laser.
Dude, this eye is actually so scary.
Ah!
Whew.
Oh, man.
I'm not long for this run.
Show me something good in there.
Game-changing item.
Yeah!
Wait.
We're gonna step.
If we can find a stepper.
That would be the ultimate steppage.
No!
Not like this.
Focus, focus, focus.
We're going back, we're going back.
We're gonna heal immediately, immediately, immediately.
Pop-pop.
Oi, oi, oi.
Tell him to the boss room.
Let's go for it.
Wish me luck.
I think it's over, but...
Oh, not the eyes.
Kill him, kill him.
Good.
Fuck you.
Okay, eyes are gone, eyes are gone.
Now we focus the boss.
Massive focus.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Damage is decent.
It's not fantastic, but it's decent.
Uh-oh.
Good, good, good, good.
What are you...
Oh!
Don't fuck up, don't fuck up, don't fuck up!
Yeah!
Don't get hit, don't get hit.
Man, my heart.
I can't take it.
Say, not I'm coming for your ass.
I'm coming for you.
But wait, maybe we can step.
I need, there's one more room we didn't explore.
This could be the game-changing moment.
Where we get a million health or something.
Actually, we could step in here.
Eee!
Don't like that.
Uh, teleport to the treasure room.
Fully healed.
That's actually pretty good.
The sun is fantastic.
Treasure room.
Wait, what?
Right.
Oh, okay, I need it to be here anyway.
There's no steppage.
Not in this economy.
We're going back.
Yep, we're gonna heal, we're moving on.
Satan, I'm coming.
Oh, I'm coming.
I'm gonna fuck you up with three hearts though, that's a little eee!
You know?
That's a little eee.
Am I missing something?
The sun!
We grabbed the sun.
We absolutely need that.
That is my trump card.
We need to absolutely heal during that fight.
I can tell you that right now.
But wait!
We're fine, we're fine, we're fine.
Uh, the sun.
Oh, thank god I can heal again, huh?
Heart room.
FTW.
As the kid said ten years ago.
Oh man, I have so much nervously inside of me right now.
Which means I'm nervous.
Wish me luck.
We're going to a shawl.
Look at this band of misfits here.
Fucking minor helmet with a bib on my mouth.
Or whatever that is.
Look, it's me!
Okay, calm down, calm down, calm down.
You there, attack him.
Thank you.
This is how I command my troops.
That was clean.
Oh dear lord.
Dear lord!
Hoish!
Ah, let's not go in there.
I'm too scared.
So, we know there's no room on the other side here, so we're not even going to go that way.
That's right.
We may look for secrets, but that's a...
Wait, I shouldn't have gone in here.
I knew there was no room.
That was a mistake.
Kill him, kill him, please.
Okay, let's go here.
What the hell are these guys?
Smells like poop.
Secret?
Man, that really smells like poop.
Holy shit.
Die!
Thank God we got a healing.
Smells like...
Okay, okay.
This way.
It's rotating!
What is this?
I've never seen this.
Open your mouth.
Say, ah!
Okay.
Come on, please.
Life-changing item.
One of these mushrooms is going to change my life.
It's not good enough.
Jesus!
What?!
Insane room!
Oh, it's over.
We're done.
How am I going to face Satan?
I can't.
Oh, God.
He's charging.
He's coming in fast.
What is this crazy room?
Oh, man.
Oh, thank God.
No!
He took it away!
Won't you let me have something?
What are you doing?
He's going to laser me?
Yep.
Wait, he killed his own friends with it.
Here comes... Yep.
Focus.
Is it laser time?
Yep, it is.
Yeah, we got him.
Holy shit.
Boss has spotted.
Boss has been located, sir.
He's in the southern perimeter.
All right, Roger.
He's going in.
Location confirmed.
Guys.
Okay, we got half a heart.
And we can heal up.
We can heal up.
Oh, dude.
Okay.
You ready?
Lock in.
Oh, my God.
Come on.
This is the third time today.
I'm fucking done.
I can't handle it.
I hate this dude.
I always appear next to him with like no HP as well, you know?
Like all the times I've tried to fight him today, I've had like shit HP.
It's crazy.
So close.
So many times.
Oh, well.
Crap.
It was a good attempt, though.
Must play Isaac with full Tommy and awake brain.
That is so true.
I am actually starving.
Like my Tommy has been rumbling.
That's how hungry I am.
But it's also my own fault because I didn't really eat that much lunch, so.
It's on me.
Next time you get his ass.
Man, I would love to get his ass.
I want to get in that pants.
I just joined the stream.
I hope it doesn't end now.
I'm sorry to be the bearer of bad news.
But we're ending now.
I also want to do great Ron genius, France.
It's coming.
I have so many things I want to do in this game.
Like...
It's too much.
It's coming down the line.
I'm going to do all of it.
Don't worry.
Also, the challenge.
Like, even the challenge today was so close.
Like, I think we got to Satan with the challenge as well.
And then, yeah, we didn't have any HP.
And it was just the same story over and over again.
Are you ever going to finish Undertale?
Are you kidding me?
I played the game through twice.
I think that's more than enough.
I don't really have the motivation to play it again, honestly.
Like, the differences between the first time I played and the second were there, but it wasn't significant enough to warrant to play the third time, for sure.
I put the blind into blind playthrough.
That's what I do.
That's the brand.
Apparently, according to everyone.
But that's fine.
I'm okay with it.
Hey, it gets food on the table.
I realize this is now going to sound like the blindness is on purpose, but trust me, it's not.
I want to win this more than you, okay?
When you get frustrated at me not figuring something out, resulting in a loss, there's nobody more frustrated about that than me, okay?
You may think you're frustrated, but I'm even more frustrated, because I want to win.
And I don't know if you know this, but...
Like, when you're playing in front of a bunch of people watching you, you kind of want to win, you know?
You want to show how good you are.
You want to, you know, yeah.
You want to be on the best behavior, I guess.
You want to really show what you can do.
It's not blindness, it's intentional rage bait.
No, it's really not.
It's just me playing the game.
I hate to turn rage bait anyway.
People started throwing it left and right lately for some reason.
It didn't used to be like that, you know?
I mean, it's fine.
You can just say that I suck at the game.
That's totally cool.
Because I do.
That's cool.
But I'm not sucking on purpose.
That's crazy.
No, it's not word of the year.
It's the worst of the year, 2025.
Oh yeah, Jimla's stream today mod is off.
Oh, is it?
Oh, you're right.
Well, they updated the game and apparently it broke a bunch of stuff, so...
I think it was Isanti who told me I should revert it, so I did.
That must have turned off the mod, I guess.
You reached Satan three times today.
You're golden.
I mean, yeah, but I didn't win.
But I guess it's nice that I... I also did learn a lot today.
Oh yeah, perfection was also a thing.
Yeah, Satan is hard as hell.
The hard thing about Satan is that he spawns these little bastards that run around and it's hard to keep track of them while dodging the feet that come down.
That's the toughest thing.
D6 roll addiction was great.
That item is busted.
Like, and you just get it on Isaac at the start of the game?
Wow.
Like, that item is off the charts.
We should start using LARP to circle-jerk Oliver content by excluding TikTok clip watchers to create a feeling of exclusivity and facilitate conversion to stream viewers.
I gotta be honest, I'm not smart enough to understand what you just said.
I have no idea what you just said.
But it sounds cool.
Stream tomorrow?
Probably not.
Tomorrow I gotta go to the doctors and do some other things and then the day after I'm going to my parents.
So no streams for a couple days at least.
That was a 30 Rock sentence?
What?
Am I too old to understand that reference?
Is that a TV show or something?
30 Rock?
Oliver, can we get seed when you start runs?
How do I do that?
Pause.
No, don't give seed?
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Hold on.
Let's have a poll.
It's been a while.
Let's have a poll about this.
Manage poll, here we go.
Wait, seed or no?
Yes?
No.
One minute.
Let's see.
What do you think?
Do we do a seed or do we don't know seed?
Yo, maybe we should start using polls for characters.
Or what next to do.
Yo, let's do that next time.
We're going to do a poll, like greed or challenge or I'm going to put in some characters or something.
Huh?
That sounds fun.
At least sometimes we can do that.
Okay, so yes is winning by quite a huge margin.
Five percent voted yes.
So I'm going to show seed next time.
If I remember, that's the big disclaimer.
Wouldn't seed ruin the predictions?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't know how that works.
I don't know if it does, does it?
If it does, then we're not going to do it.
Is that actually ruining predictions then?
Like, I don't know what you guys can get from a seed.
Like, you would have to play through it, right?
And see what it is first?
Like, you would have to speedrun or whatever.
People have the seed, they will let them see your items before they appear.
Oh!
Okay.
Is this your skill that affect prediction?
I guess, but what if you get, like, really only bad items or something?
Okay, let's just say I will show seed, but it's with the caveat that I'll probably forget half the time.
So we're going to end up evening it out.
Yeah, I'm going to try and remember.
I probably won't remember.
That's going to be how we do it.
Okay, that's a deal.
We'll do that.
Okay, I got to go eat.
Thank you so much for watching.
This was a bit of a longer one.
I appreciate you.
I'll see you next time.
Have a good one.
Ciao!